[
{"Front": "嗚呼", "Back": "ああ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相", "Back": "あい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相変わらず", "Back": "あいかわらず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愛想", "Back": "あいそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相対", "Back": "あいたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間柄", "Back": "あいだがら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愛憎", "Back": "あいにく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合間", "Back": "あいま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "曖昧", "Back": "あいまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敢えて", "Back": "あえて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仰ぐ", "Back": "あおぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "垢", "Back": "あか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "亜科", "Back": "あか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "銅", "Back": "あかがね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "証", "Back": "あかし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "赤字", "Back": "あかじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明かす", "Back": "あかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "赤ちゃん", "Back": "あかちゃん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明白", "Back": "あからさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "赤らむ", "Back": "あからむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明るい", "Back": "あかるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上がり", "Back": "あがり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上がる", "Back": "あがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商人", "Back": "あきうど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空間", "Back": "あきま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "諦め", "Back": "あきらめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呆れる", "Back": "あきれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪", "Back": "あく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灰", "Back": "あく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪日", "Back": "あくび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明くる", "Back": "あくる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憧れ", "Back": "あこがれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "顎", "Back": "あご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "麻", "Back": "あさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明後日", "Back": "あさって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "朝寝坊", "Back": "あさねぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浅ましい", "Back": "あさましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "字", "Back": "あざ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欺く", "Back": "あざむく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鮮やか", "Back": "あざやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "あざ笑う", "Back": "あざわらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "味わい", "Back": "あじわい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "東", "Back": "あずま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "焦る", "Back": "あせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彼処", "Back": "あそこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "値", "Back": "あたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "値する", "Back": "あたいする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "私", "Back": "あたし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当たり", "Back": "あたり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当たり前", "Back": "あたりまえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "他人", "Back": "あだびと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彼方此方", "Back": "あちこち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彼方", "Back": "あちら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪化", "Back": "あっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呆気ない", "Back": "あっけない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪口", "Back": "あっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "圧迫", "Back": "あっぱく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "扱い", "Back": "あつかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集まる", "Back": "あつまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誂える", "Back": "あつらえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "圧力", "Back": "あつりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当て", "Back": "あて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宛", "Back": "あて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当て字", "Back": "あてじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当てはまる", "Back": "あてはまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当てはめる", "Back": "あてはめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宛てる", "Back": "あてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "跡継ぎ", "Back": "あとつぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "後回し", "Back": "あとまわし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貴女", "Back": "あなた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彼の", "Back": "あの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溢れる", "Back": "あふれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "油絵", "Back": "あぶらえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炙る", "Back": "あぶる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甘える", "Back": "あまえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甘口", "Back": "あまくち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雨具", "Back": "あまぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天", "Back": "あまつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "網", "Back": "あみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天地", "Back": "あめつち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "操る", "Back": "あやつる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "危ぶむ", "Back": "あやぶむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過ち", "Back": "あやまち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誤る", "Back": "あやまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歩み", "Back": "あゆみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歩む", "Back": "あゆむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予め", "Back": "あらかじめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "荒らす", "Back": "あらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粗筋", "Back": "あらすじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "争い", "Back": "あらそい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改まる", "Back": "あらたまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "荒っぽい", "Back": "あらっぽい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凡ゆる", "Back": "あらゆる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現われ", "Back": "あらわれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現われる", "Back": "あらわれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有難う", "Back": "ありがとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有様", "Back": "ありさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有りのまま", "Back": "ありのまま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "或る", "Back": "ある", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "或いは", "Back": "あるいは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彼此", "Back": "あれこれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合わす", "Back": "あわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合わせ", "Back": "あわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慌ただしい", "Back": "あわただしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慌てる", "Back": "あわてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暗殺", "Back": "あんさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暗算", "Back": "あんざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暗示", "Back": "あんじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "案じる", "Back": "あんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "安静", "Back": "あんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "案の定", "Back": "あんのじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余り", "Back": "あんまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "依", "Back": "い", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "良い", "Back": "いい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伊井", "Back": "いい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "否", "Back": "いいえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "いい加減", "Back": "いいかげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言い訳", "Back": "いいわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家出", "Back": "いえで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家主", "Back": "いえぬし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "如何", "Back": "いかが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生かす", "Back": "いかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雷", "Back": "いかずち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "如何に", "Back": "いかに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "如何にも", "Back": "いかにも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怒り", "Back": "いかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怒る", "Back": "いかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歪む", "Back": "いがむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粋", "Back": "いき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "域外", "Back": "いきがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意気込む", "Back": "いきごむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経緯", "Back": "いきさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行き違い", "Back": "いきちがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行き成り", "Back": "いきなり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "異議", "Back": "いぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軍", "Back": "いくさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戦", "Back": "いくさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "育成", "Back": "いくせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幾多", "Back": "いくた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活ける", "Back": "いける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "異見", "Back": "いけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意向", "Back": "いこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "移行", "Back": "いこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "碑", "Back": "いしぶみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衣装", "Back": "いしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意地", "Back": "いじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苛める", "Back": "いじめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "移住", "Back": "いじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弄る", "Back": "いじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何れ", "Back": "いずれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "異性", "Back": "いせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遺跡", "Back": "いせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "依然", "Back": "いぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "依存", "Back": "いそん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "委託", "Back": "いたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪戯", "Back": "いたずら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頂", "Back": "いただき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戴きます", "Back": "いただきます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "至って", "Back": "いたって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "痛む", "Back": "いたむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "痛める", "Back": "いためる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炒める", "Back": "いためる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "労る", "Back": "いたわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "市", "Back": "いち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "位地", "Back": "いち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一々", "Back": "いちいち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一概に", "Back": "いちがいに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一見", "Back": "いちげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一言", "Back": "いちげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一日", "Back": "いちじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一定", "Back": "いちじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "著しい", "Back": "いちじるしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一同", "Back": "いちどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一人", "Back": "いちにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一部", "Back": "いちぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一部分", "Back": "いちぶぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一別", "Back": "いちべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一面", "Back": "いちめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一目", "Back": "いちもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一様", "Back": "いちよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一律", "Back": "いちりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一連", "Back": "いちれん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一括", "Back": "いっかつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一気", "Back": "いっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一挙に", "Back": "いっきょに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一切", "Back": "いっさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一心", "Back": "いっしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一帯", "Back": "いったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一敗", "Back": "いっぱい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一変", "Back": "いっぺん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何時", "Back": "いつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何時か", "Back": "いつか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何時でも", "Back": "いつでも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何時の間にか", "Back": "いつのまにか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何時までも", "Back": "いつまでも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何時も", "Back": "いつも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意図", "Back": "いと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "営む", "Back": "いとなむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暇", "Back": "いとま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "異動", "Back": "いどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "挑む", "Back": "いどむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "稲光", "Back": "いなびかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "古", "Back": "いにしえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祈り", "Back": "いのり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鼾", "Back": "いびき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今更", "Back": "いまさら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未だ", "Back": "いまだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "移民", "Back": "いみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "厭々", "Back": "いやいや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "卑しい", "Back": "いやしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "厭やらしい", "Back": "いやらしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愈々", "Back": "いよいよ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意欲", "Back": "いよく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苛々", "Back": "いらいら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入口", "Back": "いりくち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衣料", "Back": "いりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "威力", "Back": "いりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入る", "Back": "いる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衣類", "Back": "いるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "色々", "Back": "いろいろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "異論", "Back": "いろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所謂", "Back": "いわゆる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "印", "Back": "いん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "員", "Back": "いん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "印鑑", "Back": "いんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "陰気", "Back": "いんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "隠居", "Back": "いんきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上下", "Back": "うえした", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浮かぶ", "Back": "うかぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受かる", "Back": "うかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "含嗽", "Back": "うがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け入れ", "Back": "うけいれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け入れる", "Back": "うけいれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け継ぐ", "Back": "うけつぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け付ける", "Back": "うけつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け止める", "Back": "うけとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け取り", "Back": "うけとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受身", "Back": "うけみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動き", "Back": "うごき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潮", "Back": "うしお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "氏", "Back": "うじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "渦", "Back": "うず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "埋まる", "Back": "うずまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嘘つき", "Back": "うそつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打ち合わせ", "Back": "うちあわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打ち合わせる", "Back": "うちあわせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打ち切る", "Back": "うちきる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打ち消し", "Back": "うちけし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打ち込む", "Back": "うちこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "団扇", "Back": "うちわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内訳", "Back": "うちわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訴え", "Back": "うったえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鬱陶しい", "Back": "うっとうしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "写し", "Back": "うつし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空ろ", "Back": "うつろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "器", "Back": "うつわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雨天", "Back": "うてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腕前", "Back": "うでまえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "饂飩", "Back": "うどん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "促す", "Back": "うながす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "唸る", "Back": "うなる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自惚れ", "Back": "うぬぼれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甘い", "Back": "うまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生まれつき", "Back": "うまれつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海路", "Back": "うみじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "産む", "Back": "うむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "埋め込む", "Back": "うめこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "梅干", "Back": "うめぼし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "末", "Back": "うら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裏返し", "Back": "うらがえし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売り出し", "Back": "うりだし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売り出す", "Back": "うりだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潤う", "Back": "うるおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "五月蝿い", "Back": "うるさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売れ行き", "Back": "うれゆき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浮気", "Back": "うわき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上手", "Back": "うわて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上回る", "Back": "うわまわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "植わる", "Back": "うわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運営", "Back": "うんえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運送", "Back": "うんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運賃", "Back": "うんちん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "云々", "Back": "うんぬん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運搬", "Back": "うんぱん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運命", "Back": "うんめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運輸", "Back": "うんゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運用", "Back": "うんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会", "Back": "え", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重", "Back": "え", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "映写", "Back": "えいしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "英字", "Back": "えいじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衛生", "Back": "えいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "映像", "Back": "えいぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "英雄", "Back": "えいゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "液", "Back": "えき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役", "Back": "えき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "閲覧", "Back": "えつらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "獲物", "Back": "えもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "襟", "Back": "えり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縁", "Back": "えん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塩", "Back": "えん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "艶", "Back": "えん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "園", "Back": "えん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "円滑", "Back": "えんかつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縁側", "Back": "えんがわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沿岸", "Back": "えんがん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "婉曲", "Back": "えんきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演習", "Back": "えんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演出", "Back": "えんしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演じる", "Back": "えんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演ずる", "Back": "えんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沿線", "Back": "えんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縁談", "Back": "えんだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遠方", "Back": "えんぽう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "円満", "Back": "えんまん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尾", "Back": "お", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "於", "Back": "お", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甥", "Back": "おい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追い込む", "Back": "おいこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "美味しい", "Back": "おいしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追い出す", "Back": "おいだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "於いて", "Back": "おいて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お出でになる", "Back": "おいでになる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "老いる", "Back": "おいる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "負う", "Back": "おう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応急", "Back": "おうきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "黄金", "Back": "おうごん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "黄色", "Back": "おうしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応募", "Back": "おうぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大方", "Back": "おおかた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大柄", "Back": "おおがら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大げさ", "Back": "おおげさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大事", "Back": "おおごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大ざっぱ", "Back": "おおざっぱ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大筋", "Back": "おおすじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大空", "Back": "おおぞら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大幅", "Back": "おおはば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大水", "Back": "おおみず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公", "Back": "おおやけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お蔭", "Back": "おかげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お蔭様で", "Back": "おかげさまで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可笑しい", "Back": "おかしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "犯す", "Back": "おかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "侵す", "Back": "おかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お菜", "Back": "おかず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "臆病", "Back": "おくびょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遅らす", "Back": "おくらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遅れ", "Back": "おくれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "起こす", "Back": "おこす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行い", "Back": "おこない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "厳か", "Back": "おごそか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傲る", "Back": "おごる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長", "Back": "おさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "押さえる", "Back": "おさえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お先に", "Back": "おさきに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収まる", "Back": "おさまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "納まる", "Back": "おさまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "治まる", "Back": "おさまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お産", "Back": "おさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教え", "Back": "おしえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "惜しむ", "Back": "おしむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "押し込む", "Back": "おしこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お喋り", "Back": "おしゃべり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お洒落", "Back": "おしゃれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "押し寄せる", "Back": "おしよせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お祖父さん", "Back": "おじいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お邪魔します", "Back": "おじゃまします", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雄", "Back": "おす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お世辞", "Back": "おせじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "襲う", "Back": "おそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遅くとも", "Back": "おそくとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恐らく", "Back": "おそらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恐れ", "Back": "おそれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恐れ入る", "Back": "おそれいる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お大事に", "Back": "おだいじに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煽てる", "Back": "おだてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落ち込む", "Back": "おちこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落ち着き", "Back": "おちつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落ち葉", "Back": "おちば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落ちる", "Back": "おちる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仰っしゃる", "Back": "おっしゃる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乙", "Back": "おつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お使い", "Back": "おつかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お手上げ", "Back": "おてあげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御手洗い", "Back": "おてあらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弟", "Back": "おと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落とす", "Back": "おとす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訪れる", "Back": "おとずれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大人しい", "Back": "おとなしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "少女", "Back": "おとめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お供", "Back": "おとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衰える", "Back": "おとろえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脅かす", "Back": "おどかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脅す", "Back": "おどす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "驚き", "Back": "おどろき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同い年", "Back": "おないどし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "女子", "Back": "おなご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お願いします", "Back": "おねがいします", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "各", "Back": "おのおの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自ずから", "Back": "おのずから", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お早う", "Back": "おはよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お祖母さん", "Back": "おばあさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怯える", "Back": "おびえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夥しい", "Back": "おびただしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "帯びる", "Back": "おびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覚え", "Back": "おぼえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御負け", "Back": "おまけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お巡りさん", "Back": "おまわりさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お宮", "Back": "おみや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お襁褓", "Back": "おむつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お目出度う", "Back": "おめでとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面", "Back": "おも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思い付き", "Back": "おもいつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面白い", "Back": "おもしろい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "玩具", "Back": "おもちゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重なる", "Back": "おもなる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "趣", "Back": "おもむき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "赴く", "Back": "おもむく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重役", "Back": "おもやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重んじる", "Back": "おもんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重んずる", "Back": "おもんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お休み", "Back": "おやすみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お八", "Back": "おやつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凡そ", "Back": "およそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "及び", "Back": "および", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "及ぶ", "Back": "およぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "織", "Back": "おり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "檻", "Back": "おり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "折り返す", "Back": "おりかえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "織物", "Back": "おりもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "織る", "Back": "おる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "俺", "Back": "おれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愚か", "Back": "おろか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "疎か", "Back": "おろそか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "終わる", "Back": "おわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "音色", "Back": "おんいろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "温和", "Back": "おんわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仮", "Back": "か", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "科", "Back": "か", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "個", "Back": "か", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下位", "Back": "かい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "階", "Back": "かい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改悪", "Back": "かいあく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海運", "Back": "かいうん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改革", "Back": "かいかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貝殻", "Back": "かいがら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "階級", "Back": "かいきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海峡", "Back": "かいきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会見", "Back": "かいけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "介護", "Back": "かいご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "開催", "Back": "かいさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回収", "Back": "かいしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改修", "Back": "かいしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怪獣", "Back": "かいじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解除", "Back": "かいじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回送", "Back": "かいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "階層", "Back": "かいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "開拓", "Back": "かいたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会談", "Back": "かいだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改定", "Back": "かいてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改訂", "Back": "かいてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "街道", "Back": "かいどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "介入", "Back": "かいにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "開発", "Back": "かいはつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海抜", "Back": "かいばつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "介抱", "Back": "かいほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解剖", "Back": "かいぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回覧", "Back": "かいらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海流", "Back": "かいりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改良", "Back": "かいりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回路", "Back": "かいろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "顧みる", "Back": "かえりみる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "省みる", "Back": "かえりみる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "返る", "Back": "かえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "顔付き", "Back": "かおつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掲げる", "Back": "かかげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "踵", "Back": "かかと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "係り", "Back": "かかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "課外", "Back": "かがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書き取り", "Back": "かきとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書き取る", "Back": "かきとる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掻き回す", "Back": "かきまわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欠く", "Back": "かく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "角", "Back": "かく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "核", "Back": "かく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "格", "Back": "かく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "佳句", "Back": "かく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "画", "Back": "かく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "格差", "Back": "かくさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拡散", "Back": "かくさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "各種", "Back": "かくしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "隔週", "Back": "かくしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確信", "Back": "かくしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "革新", "Back": "かくしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確定", "Back": "かくてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "獲得", "Back": "かくとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確保", "Back": "かくほ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "革命", "Back": "かくめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確立", "Back": "かくりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賭け", "Back": "かけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掛け", "Back": "かけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "駆け足", "Back": "かけあし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家計", "Back": "かけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "駆けっこ", "Back": "かけっこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "駆ける", "Back": "かける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賭ける", "Back": "かける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ヶ月", "Back": "かげつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加工", "Back": "かこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "化合", "Back": "かごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嵩張る", "Back": "かさばる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嵩む", "Back": "かさむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風車", "Back": "かざぐるま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "畏まりました", "Back": "かしこまりました", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "華奢", "Back": "かしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "箇所", "Back": "かしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火傷", "Back": "かしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "箇条書き", "Back": "かじょうがき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "噛る", "Back": "かじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "微か", "Back": "かすか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "霞む", "Back": "かすむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "化する", "Back": "かする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "擦る", "Back": "かする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火星", "Back": "かせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "化石", "Back": "かせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "河川", "Back": "かせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "化繊", "Back": "かせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過疎", "Back": "かそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過多", "Back": "かた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "難い", "Back": "かたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "片思い", "Back": "かたおもい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敵", "Back": "かたき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気質", "Back": "かたぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "片言", "Back": "かたこと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "片付け", "Back": "かたづけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傾く", "Back": "かたぶく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傾ける", "Back": "かたむける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "固める", "Back": "かためる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偏る", "Back": "かたよる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傍ら", "Back": "かたわら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "課題", "Back": "かだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "花壇", "Back": "かだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家畜", "Back": "かちく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "画期", "Back": "かっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活発", "Back": "かっぱつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "且つ", "Back": "かつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割", "Back": "かつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嘗て", "Back": "かつて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日付", "Back": "かづけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "門", "Back": "かど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叶う", "Back": "かなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叶える", "Back": "かなえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金槌", "Back": "かなづち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉄棒", "Back": "かなぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可成", "Back": "かなり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加入", "Back": "かにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金庫", "Back": "かねぐら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予言", "Back": "かねごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兼ねて", "Back": "かねて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下番", "Back": "かばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下品", "Back": "かひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "華美", "Back": "かび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "花粉", "Back": "かふん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "株式", "Back": "かぶしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気触れる", "Back": "かぶれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貨幣", "Back": "かへい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "構え", "Back": "かまえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "構える", "Back": "かまえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加味", "Back": "かみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "噛み切る", "Back": "かみきる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過密", "Back": "かみつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瓶", "Back": "かめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "かも知れない", "Back": "かもしれない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粥", "Back": "かゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "痒い", "Back": "かゆい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揶揄う", "Back": "からかう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身体", "Back": "からだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体付き", "Back": "からだつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絡む", "Back": "からむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "借り", "Back": "かり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下吏", "Back": "かり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加留多", "Back": "かるた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "涸れる", "Back": "かれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過労", "Back": "かろう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辛うじて", "Back": "かろうじて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "側", "Back": "かわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可愛い", "Back": "かわいい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可愛がる", "Back": "かわいがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可哀想", "Back": "かわいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可愛らしい", "Back": "かわいらしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交わす", "Back": "かわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代わる", "Back": "かわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代わる代わる", "Back": "かわるがわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乾", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "管", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幹", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冠", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "館", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "簡易", "Back": "かんい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感慨", "Back": "かんがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寒気", "Back": "かんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "簡潔", "Back": "かんけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "還元", "Back": "かんげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刊行", "Back": "かんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慣行", "Back": "かんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勧告", "Back": "かんこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "看護", "Back": "かんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漢語", "Back": "かんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "換算", "Back": "かんさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "監視", "Back": "かんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慣習", "Back": "かんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観衆", "Back": "かんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "干渉", "Back": "かんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感触", "Back": "かんしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肝心", "Back": "かんじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歓声", "Back": "かんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感染", "Back": "かんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幹線", "Back": "かんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "関税", "Back": "かんぜい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "簡素", "Back": "かんそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観点", "Back": "かんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感度", "Back": "かんど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幹部", "Back": "かんぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勘弁", "Back": "かんべん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "完璧", "Back": "かんぺき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感無量", "Back": "かんむりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勧誘", "Back": "かんゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "関与", "Back": "かんよ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慣用", "Back": "かんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寛容", "Back": "かんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観覧", "Back": "かんらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "官僚", "Back": "かんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慣例", "Back": "かんれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "還暦", "Back": "かんれき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貫禄", "Back": "かんろく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緩和", "Back": "かんわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蓋", "Back": "がい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "街", "Back": "がい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外貨", "Back": "がいか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外観", "Back": "がいかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外相", "Back": "がいしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "害する", "Back": "がいする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "概説", "Back": "がいせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "該当", "Back": "がいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "街頭", "Back": "がいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "概念", "Back": "がいねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外来", "Back": "がいらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "概略", "Back": "がいりゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学芸", "Back": "がくげい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学士", "Back": "がくし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学説", "Back": "がくせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "楽譜", "Back": "がくふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学歴", "Back": "がくれき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "崖", "Back": "がけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雅致", "Back": "がち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合唱", "Back": "がっしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合致", "Back": "がっち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月日", "Back": "がっぴ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合併", "Back": "がっぺい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "癌", "Back": "がん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眼科", "Back": "がんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眼球", "Back": "がんきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眼鏡", "Back": "がんきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頑固", "Back": "がんこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "願書", "Back": "がんしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頑丈", "Back": "がんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "岩石", "Back": "がんせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "元年", "Back": "がんねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "贋物", "Back": "がんぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "元来", "Back": "がんらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生", "Back": "き", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "期", "Back": "き", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "企画", "Back": "きかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規格", "Back": "きかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着飾る", "Back": "きかざる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "器官", "Back": "きかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "季刊", "Back": "きかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "危害", "Back": "きがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気兼ね", "Back": "きがね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気軽", "Back": "きがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "危機", "Back": "きき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "聞き取り", "Back": "ききとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "効き目", "Back": "ききめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "帰京", "Back": "ききょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基金", "Back": "ききん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "棄権", "Back": "きけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "喜劇", "Back": "きげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "起源", "Back": "きげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "機構", "Back": "きこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "既婚", "Back": "きこん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記載", "Back": "きさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気障", "Back": "きざ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兆し", "Back": "きざし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兆", "Back": "きざし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軋む", "Back": "きしむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気象", "Back": "きしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "期日", "Back": "きじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記述", "Back": "きじゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奇数", "Back": "きすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "築く", "Back": "きずく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傷付く", "Back": "きずつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規制", "Back": "きせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汽船", "Back": "きせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寄贈", "Back": "きそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貴族", "Back": "きぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鍛える", "Back": "きたえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "来る", "Back": "きたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気立て", "Back": "きだて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "几帳面", "Back": "きちょうめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切っ掛け", "Back": "きっかけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "喫茶", "Back": "きっさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屹度", "Back": "きっと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規定", "Back": "きてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "起点", "Back": "きてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軌道", "Back": "きどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甲", "Back": "きのえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気配", "Back": "きはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規範", "Back": "きはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気品", "Back": "きひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気風", "Back": "きふう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "起伏", "Back": "きふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規模", "Back": "きぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気まぐれ", "Back": "きまぐれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生真面目", "Back": "きまじめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "期末", "Back": "きまつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決まり悪い", "Back": "きまりわるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決まる", "Back": "きまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記名", "Back": "きめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脚色", "Back": "きゃくしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脚本", "Back": "きゃくほん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "客観", "Back": "きゃっかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規約", "Back": "きやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "救援", "Back": "きゅうえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休学", "Back": "きゅうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "究極", "Back": "きゅうきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "窮屈", "Back": "きゅうくつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "球根", "Back": "きゅうこん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "救済", "Back": "きゅうさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "給食", "Back": "きゅうしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "給仕", "Back": "きゅうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休戦", "Back": "きゅうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旧知", "Back": "きゅうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宮殿", "Back": "きゅうでん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "窮乏", "Back": "きゅうぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丘陵", "Back": "きゅうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共", "Back": "きょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "供", "Back": "きょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "驚異", "Back": "きょうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教員", "Back": "きょういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教科", "Back": "きょうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "協会", "Back": "きょうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共感", "Back": "きょうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共学", "Back": "きょうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "協議", "Back": "きょうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教訓", "Back": "きょうくん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "境遇", "Back": "きょうぐう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強行", "Back": "きょうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強硬", "Back": "きょうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凶作", "Back": "きょうさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共産", "Back": "きょうさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教材", "Back": "きょうざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教習", "Back": "きょうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "郷愁", "Back": "きょうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教職", "Back": "きょうしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "享受", "Back": "きょうじゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "興じる", "Back": "きょうじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強制", "Back": "きょうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共存", "Back": "きょうそん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "姉妹", "Back": "きょうだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "協調", "Back": "きょうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "協定", "Back": "きょうてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脅迫", "Back": "きょうはく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共鳴", "Back": "きょうめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "郷里", "Back": "きょうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強烈", "Back": "きょうれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共和", "Back": "きょうわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "曲", "Back": "きょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "局限", "Back": "きょくげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "極端", "Back": "きょくたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "居住", "Back": "きょじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拒絶", "Back": "きょぜつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拒否", "Back": "きょひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "許容", "Back": "きょよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "距離", "Back": "きょり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寄与", "Back": "きよ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清らか", "Back": "きよらか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気楽", "Back": "きらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煌びやか", "Back": "きらびやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切り", "Back": "きり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "桐", "Back": "きり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切り替える", "Back": "きりかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気流", "Back": "きりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奇麗", "Back": "きれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切れ目", "Back": "きれめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "際", "Back": "きわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "木綿", "Back": "きわた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "極めて", "Back": "きわめて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "僅", "Back": "きん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近眼", "Back": "きんがん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緊急", "Back": "きんきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近々", "Back": "きんきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近郊", "Back": "きんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "均衡", "Back": "きんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近視", "Back": "きんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "禁じる", "Back": "きんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "禁ずる", "Back": "きんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勤勉", "Back": "きんべん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勤務", "Back": "きんむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "禁物", "Back": "きんもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勤労", "Back": "きんろう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議案", "Back": "ぎあん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戯曲", "Back": "ぎきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議決", "Back": "ぎけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議事堂", "Back": "ぎじどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "犠牲", "Back": "ぎせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偽造", "Back": "ぎぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議題", "Back": "ぎだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "技能", "Back": "ぎのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逆転", "Back": "ぎゃくてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行", "Back": "ぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "業者", "Back": "ぎょうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行政", "Back": "ぎょうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "業績", "Back": "ぎょうせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "業務", "Back": "ぎょうむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "玉", "Back": "ぎょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漁船", "Back": "ぎょせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漁村", "Back": "ぎょそん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "義理", "Back": "ぎり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "疑惑", "Back": "ぎわく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吟味", "Back": "ぎんみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区", "Back": "く", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食い違う", "Back": "くいちがう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空腹", "Back": "くうふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区画", "Back": "くかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区間", "Back": "くかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茎", "Back": "くき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区切り", "Back": "くぎり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潜る", "Back": "くぐる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "種々", "Back": "くさぐさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嚏", "Back": "くしゃみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旧事", "Back": "くじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "籤引", "Back": "くじびき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "擽ぐったい", "Back": "くすぐったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "草臥れる", "Back": "くたびれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下らない", "Back": "くだらない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "件", "Back": "くだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "口ずさむ", "Back": "くちずさむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嘴", "Back": "くちばし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "朽ちる", "Back": "くちる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屈折", "Back": "くっせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "くっ付く", "Back": "くっつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "くっ付ける", "Back": "くっつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覆す", "Back": "くつがえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "諄い", "Back": "くどい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国境", "Back": "くにざかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "首飾り", "Back": "くびかざり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "首輪", "Back": "くびわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組み合わせ", "Back": "くみあわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組み合わせる", "Back": "くみあわせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組み込む", "Back": "くみこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蔵", "Back": "くら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦しめる", "Back": "くるしめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "包む", "Back": "くるむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呉れ呉れも", "Back": "くれぐれも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呉れる", "Back": "くれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "玄人", "Back": "くろうと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "黒字", "Back": "くろじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "君主", "Back": "くんしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愚痴", "Back": "ぐち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "群", "Back": "ぐん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軍艦", "Back": "ぐんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "群集", "Back": "ぐんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軍事", "Back": "ぐんじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軍備", "Back": "ぐんび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軍服", "Back": "ぐんぷく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刑", "Back": "けい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頃", "Back": "けい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傾", "Back": "けい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "系", "Back": "けい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経過", "Back": "けいか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軽快", "Back": "けいかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "警戒", "Back": "けいかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "計器", "Back": "けいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "契機", "Back": "けいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敬具", "Back": "けいぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軽減", "Back": "けいげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掲載", "Back": "けいさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傾斜", "Back": "けいしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "形成", "Back": "けいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "形勢", "Back": "けいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軽率", "Back": "けいそつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "携帯", "Back": "けいたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "形態", "Back": "けいたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刑罰", "Back": "けいばつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経費", "Back": "けいひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "警部", "Back": "けいぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軽蔑", "Back": "けいべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経歴", "Back": "けいれき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経路", "Back": "けいろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汚す", "Back": "けがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汚らわしい", "Back": "けがらわしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汚れ", "Back": "けがれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汚れる", "Back": "けがれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "獣", "Back": "けだもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吝嗇", "Back": "けち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結核", "Back": "けっかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "血管", "Back": "けっかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決行", "Back": "けっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決算", "Back": "けっさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決勝", "Back": "けっしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結晶", "Back": "けっしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結成", "Back": "けっせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結束", "Back": "けっそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傑", "Back": "けつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決意", "Back": "けつい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決議", "Back": "けつぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結合", "Back": "けつごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決断", "Back": "けつだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欠乏", "Back": "けつぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蹴飛ばす", "Back": "けとばす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貶す", "Back": "けなす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煙たい", "Back": "けむたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煙る", "Back": "けむる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家来", "Back": "けらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "圏", "Back": "けん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "権", "Back": "けん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "権威", "Back": "けんい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兼業", "Back": "けんぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "権限", "Back": "けんげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "健在", "Back": "けんざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "懸賞", "Back": "けんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "検事", "Back": "けんじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "健全", "Back": "けんぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見地", "Back": "けんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賢明", "Back": "けんめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "倹約", "Back": "けんやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兼用", "Back": "けんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "権力", "Back": "けんりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "劇団", "Back": "げきだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "激励", "Back": "げきれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月謝", "Back": "げっしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月賦", "Back": "げっぷ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下痢", "Back": "げり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原", "Back": "げん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原形", "Back": "げんけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現行", "Back": "げんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原作", "Back": "げんさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原子", "Back": "げんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "元首", "Back": "げんしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原書", "Back": "げんしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "減少", "Back": "げんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現場", "Back": "げんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "元素", "Back": "げんそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原則", "Back": "げんそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現像", "Back": "げんぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現地", "Back": "げんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "限定", "Back": "げんてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原点", "Back": "げんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原典", "Back": "げんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "減点", "Back": "げんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原爆", "Back": "げんばく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原文", "Back": "げんぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "厳密", "Back": "げんみつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原油", "Back": "げんゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言論", "Back": "げんろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "故", "Back": "こ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戸", "Back": "こ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "児", "Back": "こ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巨", "Back": "こ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恋する", "Back": "こいする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溝", "Back": "こう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "校", "Back": "こう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好意", "Back": "こうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行為", "Back": "こうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行員", "Back": "こういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交易", "Back": "こうえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公演", "Back": "こうえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "後悔", "Back": "こうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公開", "Back": "こうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "航海", "Back": "こうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "工学", "Back": "こうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "皇居", "Back": "こうきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好況", "Back": "こうきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抗議", "Back": "こうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉱業", "Back": "こうぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "興業", "Back": "こうぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高原", "Back": "こうげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煌々と", "Back": "こうこうと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "考古学", "Back": "こうこがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交互", "Back": "こうご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "工作", "Back": "こうさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "耕作", "Back": "こうさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉱山", "Back": "こうざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "講習", "Back": "こうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交渉", "Back": "こうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高尚", "Back": "こうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行進", "Back": "こうしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "香辛料", "Back": "こうしんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "口述", "Back": "こうじゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "控除", "Back": "こうじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "向上", "Back": "こうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "降水", "Back": "こうすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "洪水", "Back": "こうずい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公然", "Back": "こうぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抗争", "Back": "こうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "構想", "Back": "こうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拘束", "Back": "こうそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "後退", "Back": "こうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "光沢", "Back": "こうたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公団", "Back": "こうだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好調", "Back": "こうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "口頭", "Back": "こうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "講読", "Back": "こうどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "購読", "Back": "こうどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "購入", "Back": "こうにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公認", "Back": "こうにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "光熱費", "Back": "こうねつひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "荒廃", "Back": "こうはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "購買", "Back": "こうばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好評", "Back": "こうひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交付", "Back": "こうふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "降伏", "Back": "こうふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "興奮", "Back": "こうふん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公募", "Back": "こうぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巧妙", "Back": "こうみょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公用", "Back": "こうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小売", "Back": "こうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "効率", "Back": "こうりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公立", "Back": "こうりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小柄", "Back": "こがら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小切手", "Back": "こぎって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国産", "Back": "こくさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国定", "Back": "こくてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国土", "Back": "こくど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "告白", "Back": "こくはく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国防", "Back": "こくぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国有", "Back": "こくゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国連", "Back": "こくれん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漕ぐ", "Back": "こぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "焦げ茶", "Back": "こげちゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "個々", "Back": "ここ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "箇箇", "Back": "ここ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心地", "Back": "ここち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心得", "Back": "こころえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心掛け", "Back": "こころがけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心掛ける", "Back": "こころがける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "志", "Back": "こころざし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "志す", "Back": "こころざす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心強い", "Back": "こころづよい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心細い", "Back": "こころぼそい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "試み", "Back": "こころみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "試みる", "Back": "こころみる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "快い", "Back": "こころよい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凝らす", "Back": "こごらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凝る", "Back": "こごる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拵える", "Back": "こしらえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "孤児", "Back": "こじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拗れる", "Back": "こじれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "故人", "Back": "こじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "梢", "Back": "こずえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "個性", "Back": "こせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戸籍", "Back": "こせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小銭", "Back": "こぜに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "固体", "Back": "こたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "答え", "Back": "こたえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "堪える", "Back": "こたえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火燵", "Back": "こたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "古代", "Back": "こだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誇張", "Back": "こちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滑稽", "Back": "こっけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国交", "Back": "こっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "骨董品", "Back": "こっとうひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "骨", "Back": "こつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "固定", "Back": "こてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事柄", "Back": "ことがら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悉く", "Back": "ことごとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言伝", "Back": "ことづて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殊に", "Back": "ことに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事によると", "Back": "ことによると", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "孤独", "Back": "こどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粉々", "Back": "こなごな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "此の", "Back": "この", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "この間", "Back": "このあいだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "この頃", "Back": "このごろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好ましい", "Back": "このましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "個別", "Back": "こべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "零す", "Back": "こぼす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "零れる", "Back": "こぼれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "細やか", "Back": "こまやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混む", "Back": "こむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "込める", "Back": "こめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "篭る", "Back": "こもる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "固有", "Back": "こゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暦", "Back": "こよみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雇用", "Back": "こよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "孤立", "Back": "こりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "懲りる", "Back": "こりる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "此れ", "Back": "これ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "此れ等", "Back": "これら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "魂", "Back": "こん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "根拠", "Back": "こんきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "根気", "Back": "こんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混血", "Back": "こんけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昆虫", "Back": "こんちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "根底", "Back": "こんてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混同", "Back": "こんどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今日は", "Back": "こんにちは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今晩は", "Back": "こんばんは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "根本", "Back": "こんぽん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御", "Back": "ご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "語彙", "Back": "ごい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濠", "Back": "ごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "業", "Back": "ごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "号", "Back": "ごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合意", "Back": "ごうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合議", "Back": "ごうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強気", "Back": "ごうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合成", "Back": "ごうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "護衛", "Back": "ごえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "語句", "Back": "ごく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "極楽", "Back": "ごくらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ご苦労様", "Back": "ごくろうさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "語源", "Back": "ごげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誤差", "Back": "ごさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ご座います", "Back": "ございます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ご馳走", "Back": "ごちそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ご馳走さま", "Back": "ごちそうさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "毎", "Back": "ごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "碁盤", "Back": "ごばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ご無沙汰", "Back": "ごぶさた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誤魔化す", "Back": "ごまかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御免ください", "Back": "ごめんください", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御免なさい", "Back": "ごめんなさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御覧なさい", "Back": "ごらんなさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "佐", "Back": "さ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再", "Back": "さい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差異", "Back": "さい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歳", "Back": "さい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再会", "Back": "さいかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "災害", "Back": "さいがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "細菌", "Back": "さいきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "細工", "Back": "さいく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採掘", "Back": "さいくつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採決", "Back": "さいけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再建", "Back": "さいけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再現", "Back": "さいげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採算", "Back": "さいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採集", "Back": "さいしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再生", "Back": "さいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "最善", "Back": "さいぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採択", "Back": "さいたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再発", "Back": "さいはつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "栽培", "Back": "さいばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "細胞", "Back": "さいぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採用", "Back": "さいよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遮る", "Back": "さえぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "囀る", "Back": "さえずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冴える", "Back": "さえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "竿", "Back": "さお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "栄える", "Back": "さかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "杯", "Back": "さかずき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逆立ち", "Back": "さかだち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逆上る", "Back": "さかのぼる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盛る", "Back": "さかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差額", "Back": "さがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下がる", "Back": "さがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一昨昨日", "Back": "さきおととい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先に", "Back": "さきに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詐欺", "Back": "さぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作", "Back": "さく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "策", "Back": "さく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "柵", "Back": "さく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "削減", "Back": "さくげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "錯誤", "Back": "さくご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作戦", "Back": "さくせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作物", "Back": "さくぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叫び", "Back": "さけび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裂ける", "Back": "さける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捧げる", "Back": "ささげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差し掛かる", "Back": "さしかかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指図", "Back": "さしず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差し出す", "Back": "さしだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差し支える", "Back": "さしつかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差し引く", "Back": "さしひく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "些事", "Back": "さじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "授ける", "Back": "さずける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嘸", "Back": "さぞ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定まる", "Back": "さだまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定める", "Back": "さだめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "錯覚", "Back": "さっかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "早急", "Back": "さっきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "察する", "Back": "さっする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冊", "Back": "さつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殺人", "Back": "さつじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偖", "Back": "さて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悟る", "Back": "さとる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真実", "Back": "さな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裁く", "Back": "さばく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "錆び", "Back": "さび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "左程", "Back": "さほど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "様", "Back": "さま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "三味線", "Back": "さみせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "侍", "Back": "さむらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "然も", "Back": "さも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作用", "Back": "さよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "左様なら", "Back": "さようなら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拐う", "Back": "さらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "爽やか", "Back": "さわやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "障る", "Back": "さわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酸", "Back": "さん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酸化", "Back": "さんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "山岳", "Back": "さんがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "産休", "Back": "さんきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "桟橋", "Back": "さんきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "参議院", "Back": "さんぎいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "産後", "Back": "さんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "産出", "Back": "さんしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "参照", "Back": "さんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "参上", "Back": "さんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賛成", "Back": "さんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賛美", "Back": "さんび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "産婦人科", "Back": "さんふじんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "産物", "Back": "さんぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "山腹", "Back": "さんぷく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "山脈", "Back": "さんみゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "財", "Back": "ざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "財源", "Back": "ざいげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "在庫", "Back": "ざいこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "財政", "Back": "ざいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "座談会", "Back": "ざだんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雑貨", "Back": "ざっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雑", "Back": "ざつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雑談", "Back": "ざつだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雑木", "Back": "ざつぼく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "座標", "Back": "ざひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "残金", "Back": "ざんきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "残酷", "Back": "ざんこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "残高", "Back": "ざんだか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "死", "Back": "し", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "次", "Back": "し", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕上がり", "Back": "しあがり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕上げ", "Back": "しあげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕上げる", "Back": "しあげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明々後日", "Back": "しあさって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飼育", "Back": "しいく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強いて", "Back": "しいて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強いる", "Back": "しいる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕入れる", "Back": "しいれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歯科", "Back": "しか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "資格", "Back": "しかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "視覚", "Back": "しかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕掛け", "Back": "しかけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕掛ける", "Back": "しかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "然し", "Back": "しかし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "然しながら", "Back": "しかしながら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "而も", "Back": "しかも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "市街", "Back": "しがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指揮", "Back": "しき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "色彩", "Back": "しきさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "式場", "Back": "しきじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "為来り", "Back": "しきたり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頻りに", "Back": "しきりに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕切る", "Back": "しきる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "資金", "Back": "しきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "施行", "Back": "しぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕組み", "Back": "しくみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "死刑", "Back": "しけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湿気る", "Back": "しける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思考", "Back": "しこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "志向", "Back": "しこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嗜好", "Back": "しこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "視察", "Back": "しさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "資産", "Back": "しさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刺繍", "Back": "ししゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支持", "Back": "しじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指示", "Back": "しじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雫", "Back": "しずく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沈める", "Back": "しずめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "施設", "Back": "しせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "子息", "Back": "しそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慕う", "Back": "したう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "従って", "Back": "したがって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下心", "Back": "したごころ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "親しむ", "Back": "したしむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下調べ", "Back": "したしらべ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下地", "Back": "したじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "認める", "Back": "したためる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕立てる", "Back": "したてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下取り", "Back": "したどり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下火", "Back": "したび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "失格", "Back": "しっかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確り", "Back": "しっかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "質素", "Back": "しっそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "失調", "Back": "しっちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嫉妬", "Back": "しっと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尻尾", "Back": "しっぽ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "室", "Back": "しつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "質疑", "Back": "しつぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "躾", "Back": "しつけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕付ける", "Back": "しつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指摘", "Back": "してき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "視点", "Back": "してん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "萎びる", "Back": "しなびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嫋か", "Back": "しなやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屎尿", "Back": "しにょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凌ぐ", "Back": "しのぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "始発", "Back": "しはつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "芝", "Back": "しば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屡", "Back": "しばしば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暫く", "Back": "しばらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "痺れる", "Back": "しびれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "渋い", "Back": "しぶい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "私物", "Back": "しぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "司法", "Back": "しほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脂肪", "Back": "しぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "志望", "Back": "しぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "萎む", "Back": "しぼむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕舞", "Back": "しまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕舞う", "Back": "しまう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "始末", "Back": "しまつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "泌み泌み", "Back": "しみじみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "染みる", "Back": "しみる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "使命", "Back": "しめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "締め切り", "Back": "しめきり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "僕", "Back": "しもべ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "社交", "Back": "しゃこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "謝絶", "Back": "しゃぜつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "社宅", "Back": "しゃたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吃逆", "Back": "しゃっくり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "喋る", "Back": "しゃべる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "斜面", "Back": "しゃめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "洒落", "Back": "しゃらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "洒落る", "Back": "しゃれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "視野", "Back": "しや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "種", "Back": "しゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衆", "Back": "しゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "周", "Back": "しゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収益", "Back": "しゅうえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修学", "Back": "しゅうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "周期", "Back": "しゅうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衆議院", "Back": "しゅうぎいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "就業", "Back": "しゅうぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修行", "Back": "しゅうぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集計", "Back": "しゅうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "襲撃", "Back": "しゅうげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収支", "Back": "しゅうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "終始", "Back": "しゅうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修士", "Back": "しゅうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収集", "Back": "しゅうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修飾", "Back": "しゅうしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "終日", "Back": "しゅうじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "執着", "Back": "しゅうじゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収容", "Back": "しゅうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修了", "Back": "しゅうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "守衛", "Back": "しゅえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主演", "Back": "しゅえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主観", "Back": "しゅかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祝賀", "Back": "しゅくが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宿命", "Back": "しゅくめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主権", "Back": "しゅけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手芸", "Back": "しゅげい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主催", "Back": "しゅさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取材", "Back": "しゅざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "趣旨", "Back": "しゅし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主食", "Back": "しゅしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主人公", "Back": "しゅじんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主体", "Back": "しゅたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主題", "Back": "しゅだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出血", "Back": "しゅっけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出産", "Back": "しゅっさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出社", "Back": "しゅっしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出生", "Back": "しゅっしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出世", "Back": "しゅっせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出費", "Back": "しゅっぴ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出品", "Back": "しゅっぴん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出演", "Back": "しゅつえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出題", "Back": "しゅつだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出動", "Back": "しゅつどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主導", "Back": "しゅどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主任", "Back": "しゅにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "首脳", "Back": "しゅのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "守備", "Back": "しゅび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手法", "Back": "しゅほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "私有", "Back": "しゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "諸", "Back": "しょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "背負う", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "象", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "症", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傷", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消去", "Back": "しょうきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衝撃", "Back": "しょうげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "証言", "Back": "しょうげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "証拠", "Back": "しょうこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消耗", "Back": "しょうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "照合", "Back": "しょうごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詳細", "Back": "しょうさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昇進", "Back": "しょうしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "少数", "Back": "しょうすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "称する", "Back": "しょうする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消息", "Back": "しょうそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "承諾", "Back": "しょうだく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "象徴", "Back": "しょうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小児科", "Back": "しょうにか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "証人", "Back": "しょうにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "照明", "Back": "しょうめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勝利", "Back": "しょうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奨励", "Back": "しょうれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "職員", "Back": "しょくいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "植民地", "Back": "しょくみんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "職務", "Back": "しょくむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "諸君", "Back": "しょくん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所在", "Back": "しょざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所々", "Back": "しょしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所持", "Back": "しょじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所属", "Back": "しょぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "処置", "Back": "しょち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所定", "Back": "しょてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所得", "Back": "しょとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "初版", "Back": "しょはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "処罰", "Back": "しょばつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書評", "Back": "しょひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "処分", "Back": "しょぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "庶民", "Back": "しょみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "庶務", "Back": "しょむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "私用", "Back": "しよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕様", "Back": "しよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "使用人", "Back": "しようにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調べ", "Back": "しらべ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知り合い", "Back": "しりあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退く", "Back": "しりぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退ける", "Back": "しりぞける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記す", "Back": "しるす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指令", "Back": "しれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代", "Back": "しろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "皺", "Back": "しわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新", "Back": "しん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進化", "Back": "しんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殿", "Back": "しんがり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "審議", "Back": "しんぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進行", "Back": "しんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新興", "Back": "しんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "振興", "Back": "しんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申告", "Back": "しんこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新婚", "Back": "しんこん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "審査", "Back": "しんさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紳士", "Back": "しんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進出", "Back": "しんしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信者", "Back": "しんじゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真珠", "Back": "しんじゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心中", "Back": "しんじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心情", "Back": "しんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新人", "Back": "しんじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "神聖", "Back": "しんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "親善", "Back": "しんぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真相", "Back": "しんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新築", "Back": "しんちく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進呈", "Back": "しんてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進展", "Back": "しんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "神殿", "Back": "しんでん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進度", "Back": "しんど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "振動", "Back": "しんどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新入生", "Back": "しんにゅうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信任", "Back": "しんにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "審判", "Back": "しんばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "神秘", "Back": "しんぴ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辛抱", "Back": "しんぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真理", "Back": "しんり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "侵略", "Back": "しんりゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "診療", "Back": "しんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進路", "Back": "しんろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自覚", "Back": "じかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地方", "Back": "じかた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自我", "Back": "じが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "磁気", "Back": "じき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "磁器", "Back": "じき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事業", "Back": "じぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地形", "Back": "じぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軸", "Back": "じく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自己", "Back": "じこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事項", "Back": "じこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時刻表", "Back": "じこくひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地獄", "Back": "じごく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時差", "Back": "じさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自在", "Back": "じざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自主", "Back": "じしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自首", "Back": "じしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辞職", "Back": "じしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自信", "Back": "じしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事前", "Back": "じぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自尊心", "Back": "じそんしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "持続", "Back": "じぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "字体", "Back": "じたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辞退", "Back": "じたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実質", "Back": "じっしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実践", "Back": "じっせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実態", "Back": "じったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実費", "Back": "じっぴ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "十分", "Back": "じっぷん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実", "Back": "じつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実業家", "Back": "じつぎょうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実情", "Back": "じつじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自転", "Back": "じてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自動詞", "Back": "じどうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地主", "Back": "じぬし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "耳鼻科", "Back": "じびか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地元", "Back": "じもと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弱", "Back": "じゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若干", "Back": "じゃっかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "砂利", "Back": "じゃり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "じゃん拳", "Back": "じゃんけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "住", "Back": "じゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "従業員", "Back": "じゅうぎょういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "従事", "Back": "じゅうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "充実", "Back": "じゅうじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "十字路", "Back": "じゅうじろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絨毯", "Back": "じゅうたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "柔軟", "Back": "じゅうなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重複", "Back": "じゅうふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重宝", "Back": "じゅうほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "従来", "Back": "じゅうらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塾", "Back": "じゅく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "樹木", "Back": "じゅもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "樹立", "Back": "じゅりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "準急", "Back": "じゅんきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "準じる", "Back": "じゅんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "準ずる", "Back": "じゅんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助", "Back": "じょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "情", "Back": "じょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "畳", "Back": "じょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尉", "Back": "じょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嬢", "Back": "じょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "状", "Back": "じょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上位", "Back": "じょうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上演", "Back": "じょうえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "城下", "Back": "じょうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗客", "Back": "じょうかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上空", "Back": "じょうくう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上司", "Back": "じょうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "情緒", "Back": "じょうしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上昇", "Back": "じょうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "情勢", "Back": "じょうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "情熱", "Back": "じょうねつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丈夫", "Back": "じょうふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "譲歩", "Back": "じょうほ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "条約", "Back": "じょうやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上陸", "Back": "じょうりく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蒸留", "Back": "じょうりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "除外", "Back": "じょがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助言", "Back": "じょげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徐行", "Back": "じょこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "女史", "Back": "じょし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助詞", "Back": "じょし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助動詞", "Back": "じょどうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自立", "Back": "じりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人", "Back": "じん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人格", "Back": "じんかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人材", "Back": "じんざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迅速", "Back": "じんそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人体", "Back": "じんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人民", "Back": "じんみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人目", "Back": "じんもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水気", "Back": "すいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水源", "Back": "すいげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "推進", "Back": "すいしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水洗", "Back": "すいせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吹奏", "Back": "すいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "推測", "Back": "すいそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水田", "Back": "すいでん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "推理", "Back": "すいり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "数詞", "Back": "すうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "崇拝", "Back": "すうはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "据え付ける", "Back": "すえつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "据える", "Back": "すえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清々しい", "Back": "すがすがしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過ぎ", "Back": "すぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "救い", "Back": "すくい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掬う", "Back": "すくう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "少なくとも", "Back": "すくなくとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直ぐ", "Back": "すぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "健やか", "Back": "すこやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濯ぐ", "Back": "すすぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進み", "Back": "すすみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勧め", "Back": "すすめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裾", "Back": "すそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "廃れる", "Back": "すたれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酸っぱい", "Back": "すっぱい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素敵", "Back": "すてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "即ち", "Back": "すなわち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素早い", "Back": "すばやい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "済ます", "Back": "すます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "澄ます", "Back": "すます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "済まない", "Back": "すまない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "済みません", "Back": "すみません", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天皇", "Back": "すめらぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刷り", "Back": "すり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剃る", "Back": "する", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "擦れ違い", "Back": "すれちがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "すれ違う", "Back": "すれちがう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "擦れる", "Back": "すれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "図々しい", "Back": "ずうずうしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ずぶ濡れ", "Back": "ずぶぬれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "製", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生育", "Back": "せいいく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成果", "Back": "せいか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正解", "Back": "せいかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正規", "Back": "せいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正義", "Back": "せいぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生計", "Back": "せいけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "政権", "Back": "せいけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "精巧", "Back": "せいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制裁", "Back": "せいさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "政策", "Back": "せいさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清算", "Back": "せいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "星座", "Back": "せいざ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生死", "Back": "せいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "静止", "Back": "せいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "青春", "Back": "せいしゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "聖書", "Back": "せいしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誠実", "Back": "せいじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成熟", "Back": "せいじゅく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清純", "Back": "せいじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正常", "Back": "せいじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制する", "Back": "せいする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "整然", "Back": "せいぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盛装", "Back": "せいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盛大", "Back": "せいだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清濁", "Back": "せいだく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制定", "Back": "せいてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "静的", "Back": "せいてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "製鉄", "Back": "せいてつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "晴天", "Back": "せいてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正当", "Back": "せいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成年", "Back": "せいねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制服", "Back": "せいふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "征服", "Back": "せいふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "製法", "Back": "せいほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "精密", "Back": "せいみつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "声明", "Back": "せいめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "姓名", "Back": "せいめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制約", "Back": "せいやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生理", "Back": "せいり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勢力", "Back": "せいりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "整列", "Back": "せいれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "急かす", "Back": "せかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伜", "Back": "せがれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "責務", "Back": "せきむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世辞", "Back": "せじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世帯", "Back": "せたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世代", "Back": "せだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切開", "Back": "せっかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "接触", "Back": "せっしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "設置", "Back": "せっち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "折衷", "Back": "せっちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "設定", "Back": "せってい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "説得", "Back": "せっとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "節", "Back": "せつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切実", "Back": "せつじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "接続詞", "Back": "せつぞくし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切ない", "Back": "せつない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "設立", "Back": "せつりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "攻め", "Back": "せめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世論", "Back": "せろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仙", "Back": "せん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前", "Back": "せん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繊維", "Back": "せんい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "選挙", "Back": "せんきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宣教", "Back": "せんきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宣言", "Back": "せんげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先行", "Back": "せんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "選考", "Back": "せんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戦災", "Back": "せんさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "専修", "Back": "せんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戦術", "Back": "せんじゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潜水", "Back": "せんすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先先月", "Back": "せんせんげつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先先週", "Back": "せんせんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先代", "Back": "せんだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先だって", "Back": "せんだって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先着", "Back": "せんちゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先天的", "Back": "せんてんてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戦闘", "Back": "せんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潜入", "Back": "せんにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "船舶", "Back": "せんぱく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "専用", "Back": "せんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "占領", "Back": "せんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戦力", "Back": "せんりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "税務署", "Back": "ぜいむしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "是正", "Back": "ぜせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絶版", "Back": "ぜっぱん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絶望", "Back": "ぜつぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "是非とも", "Back": "ぜひとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膳", "Back": "ぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "禅", "Back": "ぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全快", "Back": "ぜんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全盛", "Back": "ぜんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前提", "Back": "ぜんてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前途", "Back": "ぜんと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全滅", "Back": "ぜんめつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "善良", "Back": "ぜんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前例", "Back": "ぜんれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "僧", "Back": "そう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沿う", "Back": "そう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "添う", "Back": "そう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "総", "Back": "そう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相応", "Back": "そうおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "総会", "Back": "そうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "創刊", "Back": "そうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "送金", "Back": "そうきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "走行", "Back": "そうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "総合", "Back": "そうごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捜査", "Back": "そうさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捜索", "Back": "そうさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "然うして", "Back": "そうして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "装飾", "Back": "そうしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "操縦", "Back": "そうじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "創造", "Back": "そうぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "壮大", "Back": "そうだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "騒動", "Back": "そうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遭難", "Back": "そうなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相場", "Back": "そうば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "装備", "Back": "そうび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "創立", "Back": "そうりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "添える", "Back": "そえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "即座に", "Back": "そくざに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "促進", "Back": "そくしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "即する", "Back": "そくする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "束縛", "Back": "そくばく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "側面", "Back": "そくめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其処", "Back": "そこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其処で", "Back": "そこで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "損なう", "Back": "そこなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其処ら", "Back": "そこら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素材", "Back": "そざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "阻止", "Back": "そし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "然して", "Back": "そして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訴訟", "Back": "そしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "育ち", "Back": "そだち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "措置", "Back": "そち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其方", "Back": "そちら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素っ気ない", "Back": "そっけない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "率直", "Back": "そっちょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外方", "Back": "そっぽ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "備え付ける", "Back": "そなえつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "備わる", "Back": "そなわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "その上", "Back": "そのうえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "その内", "Back": "そのうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "その為", "Back": "そのため", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "その外", "Back": "そのほか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其の儘", "Back": "そのまま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "聳える", "Back": "そびえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素朴", "Back": "そぼく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "染まる", "Back": "そまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "背く", "Back": "そむく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "染める", "Back": "そめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逸らす", "Back": "そらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反り", "Back": "そり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れ", "Back": "それ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れから", "Back": "それから", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "各々", "Back": "それぞれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れで", "Back": "それで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れでは", "Back": "それでは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れでも", "Back": "それでも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れ共", "Back": "それとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れに", "Back": "それに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れ程", "Back": "それほど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "其れ故", "Back": "それゆえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揃い", "Back": "そろい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徐々", "Back": "そろそろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "損失", "Back": "そんしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "存続", "Back": "そんぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沿い", "Back": "ぞい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "像", "Back": "ぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増強", "Back": "ぞうきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蔵相", "Back": "ぞうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増進", "Back": "ぞうしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "他意", "Back": "たい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対応", "Back": "たいおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退化", "Back": "たいか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体格", "Back": "たいかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大概", "Back": "たいがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退学", "Back": "たいがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大金", "Back": "たいきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "待遇", "Back": "たいぐう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対決", "Back": "たいけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体験", "Back": "たいけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対抗", "Back": "たいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対して", "Back": "たいして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大衆", "Back": "たいしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対処", "Back": "たいしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退職", "Back": "たいしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退治", "Back": "たいじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "態勢", "Back": "たいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対談", "Back": "たいだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対等", "Back": "たいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滞納", "Back": "たいのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対比", "Back": "たいひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大部", "Back": "たいぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対辺", "Back": "たいへん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "待望", "Back": "たいぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怠慢", "Back": "たいまん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対面", "Back": "たいめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対立", "Back": "たいりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体力", "Back": "たいりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対話", "Back": "たいわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "耐える", "Back": "たえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絶える", "Back": "たえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高", "Back": "たか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高まる", "Back": "たかまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "焚火", "Back": "たきび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沢山", "Back": "たくさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逞しい", "Back": "たくましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巧み", "Back": "たくみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "類", "Back": "たぐい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丈", "Back": "たけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "足し算", "Back": "たしざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "多数決", "Back": "たすうけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助け", "Back": "たすけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "携わる", "Back": "たずさわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漂う", "Back": "ただよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立方", "Back": "たちかた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "忽ち", "Back": "たちまち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立ち寄る", "Back": "たちよる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "達者", "Back": "たっしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "達成", "Back": "たっせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尊い", "Back": "たっとい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貴い", "Back": "たっとい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尊ぶ", "Back": "たっとぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絶つ", "Back": "たつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盾", "Back": "たて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "建前", "Back": "たてまえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奉る", "Back": "たてまつる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仮令", "Back": "たとえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "例え", "Back": "たとえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "他動詞", "Back": "たどうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辿り着く", "Back": "たどりつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辿る", "Back": "たどる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掌", "Back": "たなごころ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "楽しむ", "Back": "たのしむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頼み", "Back": "たのみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煙草", "Back": "たばこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "度々", "Back": "たびたび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "他方", "Back": "たほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "多忙", "Back": "たぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "給う", "Back": "たまう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偶に", "Back": "たまに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "堪らない", "Back": "たまらない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溜まり", "Back": "たまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賜る", "Back": "たまわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "例", "Back": "ためし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "躊躇う", "Back": "ためらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保つ", "Back": "たもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "容易い", "Back": "たやすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "多様", "Back": "たよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弛み", "Back": "たるみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弛む", "Back": "たるむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誰", "Back": "たれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "垂れる", "Back": "たれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歎", "Back": "たん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反", "Back": "たん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単一", "Back": "たんいつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短歌", "Back": "たんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "担架", "Back": "たんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短気", "Back": "たんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "探検", "Back": "たんけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短縮", "Back": "たんしゅく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "箪笥", "Back": "たんす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炭素", "Back": "たんそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短大", "Back": "たんだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単調", "Back": "たんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単独", "Back": "たんどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短波", "Back": "たんぱ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蛋白質", "Back": "たんぱくしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "第", "Back": "だい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "第一", "Back": "だいいち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大胆", "Back": "だいたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "台無し", "Back": "だいなし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大便", "Back": "だいべん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代弁", "Back": "だいべん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "台本", "Back": "だいほん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代用", "Back": "だいよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打開", "Back": "だかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妥協", "Back": "だきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妥結", "Back": "だけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打撃", "Back": "だげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "駄作", "Back": "ださく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脱出", "Back": "だっしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脱する", "Back": "だっする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脱退", "Back": "だったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "騙す", "Back": "だます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怠い", "Back": "だるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "壇", "Back": "だん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "団結", "Back": "だんけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "断言", "Back": "だんげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "断然", "Back": "だんぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "段々", "Back": "だんだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旦那", "Back": "だんな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "断面", "Back": "だんめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弾力", "Back": "だんりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "治安", "Back": "ちあん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近付く", "Back": "ちかづく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "違える", "Back": "ちがえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "契る", "Back": "ちぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "畜産", "Back": "ちくさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "畜生", "Back": "ちくしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蓄積", "Back": "ちくせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知性", "Back": "ちせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乳", "Back": "ちち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "父母", "Back": "ちちはは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縮まる", "Back": "ちぢまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "窒息", "Back": "ちっそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "些とも", "Back": "ちっとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "秩序", "Back": "ちつじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知的", "Back": "ちてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "著", "Back": "ちゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着", "Back": "ちゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着手", "Back": "ちゃくしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着色", "Back": "ちゃくしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着席", "Back": "ちゃくせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着目", "Back": "ちゃくもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着陸", "Back": "ちゃくりく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着工", "Back": "ちゃっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茶の間", "Back": "ちゃのま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茶の湯", "Back": "ちゃのゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昼間", "Back": "ちゅうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宙返り", "Back": "ちゅうがえり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中継", "Back": "ちゅうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "忠告", "Back": "ちゅうこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中指", "Back": "ちゅうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中傷", "Back": "ちゅうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "忠実", "Back": "ちゅうじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中枢", "Back": "ちゅうすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抽選", "Back": "ちゅうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中断", "Back": "ちゅうだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中腹", "Back": "ちゅうっぱら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中毒", "Back": "ちゅうどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仲人", "Back": "ちゅうにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昼飯", "Back": "ちゅうはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中立", "Back": "ちゅうりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中和", "Back": "ちゅうわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腸", "Back": "ちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蝶", "Back": "ちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "超", "Back": "ちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "庁", "Back": "ちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調印", "Back": "ちょういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "聴覚", "Back": "ちょうかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長官", "Back": "ちょうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "聴講", "Back": "ちょうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徴収", "Back": "ちょうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "聴診器", "Back": "ちょうしんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "挑戦", "Back": "ちょうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長大", "Back": "ちょうだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調停", "Back": "ちょうてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恰度", "Back": "ちょうど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長編", "Back": "ちょうへん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丁目", "Back": "ちょうめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調理", "Back": "ちょうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調和", "Back": "ちょうわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直面", "Back": "ちょくめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "著書", "Back": "ちょしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貯蓄", "Back": "ちょちく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直感", "Back": "ちょっかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一寸", "Back": "ちょっと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "著名", "Back": "ちょめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塵取り", "Back": "ちりとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "治療", "Back": "ちりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賃金", "Back": "ちんぎん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沈殿", "Back": "ちんでん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沈没", "Back": "ちんぼつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沈黙", "Back": "ちんもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "陳列", "Back": "ちんれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追及", "Back": "ついきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追跡", "Back": "ついせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "次いで", "Back": "ついで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追放", "Back": "ついほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "費やす", "Back": "ついやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "墜落", "Back": "ついらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通", "Back": "つう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "痛感", "Back": "つうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通常", "Back": "つうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "痛切", "Back": "つうせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "杖", "Back": "つえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遣い", "Back": "つかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "使い道", "Back": "つかいみち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕える", "Back": "つかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "司る", "Back": "つかさどる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "束の間", "Back": "つかのま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付き", "Back": "つき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付き合う", "Back": "つきあう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月並み", "Back": "つきなみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尽きる", "Back": "つきる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "継ぎ目", "Back": "つぎめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吐く", "Back": "つく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尽くす", "Back": "つくす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作り", "Back": "つくり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "造り", "Back": "つくり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "造る", "Back": "つくる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繕う", "Back": "つくろう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "接ぐ", "Back": "つぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "継ぐ", "Back": "つぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付け加える", "Back": "つけくわえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "告げる", "Back": "つげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辻褄", "Back": "つじつま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "途中", "Back": "つちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突っ張る", "Back": "つっぱる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "筒", "Back": "つつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "銃", "Back": "つつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突く", "Back": "つつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慎む", "Back": "つつしむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝言", "Back": "つてごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勤まる", "Back": "つとまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勤め先", "Back": "つとめさき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "努めて", "Back": "つとめて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "津波", "Back": "つなみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抓る", "Back": "つねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "募る", "Back": "つのる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "唾", "Back": "つば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呟く", "Back": "つぶやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瞑る", "Back": "つぶる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "壷", "Back": "つぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蕾", "Back": "つぼみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "躓く", "Back": "つまずく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "摘む", "Back": "つまむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詰らない", "Back": "つまらない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詰まり", "Back": "つまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "積もり", "Back": "つもり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "露", "Back": "つゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強まる", "Back": "つよまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強める", "Back": "つよめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連なる", "Back": "つらなる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貫く", "Back": "つらぬく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連ねる", "Back": "つらねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "釣り", "Back": "つり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吊り革", "Back": "つりかわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "釣鐘", "Back": "つりがね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吊るす", "Back": "つるす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手当て", "Back": "てあて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体", "Back": "てい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "提供", "Back": "ていきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定義", "Back": "ていぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "提携", "Back": "ていけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体裁", "Back": "ていさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "梯子", "Back": "ていし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定食", "Back": "ていしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "提示", "Back": "ていじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訂正", "Back": "ていせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "停滞", "Back": "ていたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "邸宅", "Back": "ていたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定年", "Back": "ていねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "堤防", "Back": "ていぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手遅れ", "Back": "ておくれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手数", "Back": "てかず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手掛かり", "Back": "てがかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手掛ける", "Back": "てがける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手軽", "Back": "てがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "的", "Back": "てき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適応", "Back": "てきおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適宜", "Back": "てきぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適性", "Back": "てきせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手際", "Back": "てぎわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手順", "Back": "てじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手錠", "Back": "てじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手近", "Back": "てぢか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉄鋼", "Back": "てっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徹する", "Back": "てっする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉄片", "Back": "てっぺん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手配", "Back": "てはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手筈", "Back": "てはず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手引き", "Back": "てびき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手本", "Back": "てほん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手回し", "Back": "てまわし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手元", "Back": "てもと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "照り返す", "Back": "てりかえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手分け", "Back": "てわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "店", "Back": "てん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "点火", "Back": "てんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転回", "Back": "てんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転換", "Back": "てんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転居", "Back": "てんきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転勤", "Back": "てんきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "点検", "Back": "てんけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転校", "Back": "てんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天国", "Back": "てんごく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天才", "Back": "てんさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天災", "Back": "てんさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "展示", "Back": "てんじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天井", "Back": "てんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転じる", "Back": "てんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "点線", "Back": "てんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天体", "Back": "てんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転転", "Back": "てんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転任", "Back": "てんにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "展望", "Back": "てんぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転落", "Back": "てんらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出合う", "Back": "であう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出入り口", "Back": "でいりぐち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出来物", "Back": "できもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出切る", "Back": "できる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出くわす", "Back": "でくわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出鱈目", "Back": "でたらめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出直し", "Back": "でなおし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "田園", "Back": "でんえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電源", "Back": "でんげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝説", "Back": "でんせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電線", "Back": "でんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝達", "Back": "でんたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝来", "Back": "でんらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "問い合わせる", "Back": "といあわせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "問屋", "Back": "といや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "問う", "Back": "とう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "棟", "Back": "とう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "等", "Back": "とう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "陶器", "Back": "とうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "等級", "Back": "とうきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "討議", "Back": "とうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "登校", "Back": "とうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "統合", "Back": "とうごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "倒産", "Back": "とうさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "投資", "Back": "とうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "統治", "Back": "とうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "統制", "Back": "とうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当選", "Back": "とうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逃走", "Back": "とうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "統率", "Back": "とうそつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "到達", "Back": "とうたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "到底", "Back": "とうてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丁々", "Back": "とうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "投入", "Back": "とうにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当人", "Back": "とうにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逃亡", "Back": "とうぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冬眠", "Back": "とうみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "登録", "Back": "とうろく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "討論", "Back": "とうろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遠ざかる", "Back": "とおざかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遠回り", "Back": "とおまわり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通りかかる", "Back": "とおりかかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兎角", "Back": "とかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "咎める", "Back": "とがめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時折", "Back": "ときおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "跡切れる", "Back": "とぎれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "説く", "Back": "とく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特技", "Back": "とくぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特産", "Back": "とくさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特集", "Back": "とくしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "得点", "Back": "とくてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特派", "Back": "とくは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特有", "Back": "とくゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "研ぐ", "Back": "とぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刺", "Back": "とげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遂げる", "Back": "とげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "床", "Back": "とこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所が", "Back": "ところが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所で", "Back": "ところで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年頃", "Back": "としごろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年寄り", "Back": "としより", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戸締り", "Back": "とじまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "途上", "Back": "とじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "綴じる", "Back": "とじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "途絶える", "Back": "とだえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特許", "Back": "とっきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "疾っくに", "Back": "とっくに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特権", "Back": "とっけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "咄嗟", "Back": "とっさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取っ手", "Back": "とって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突破", "Back": "とっぱ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突如", "Back": "とつじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迚も", "Back": "とても", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "整える", "Back": "ととのえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "届け", "Back": "とどけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滞る", "Back": "とどこおる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "止まる", "Back": "とどまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "留める", "Back": "とどめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "止める", "Back": "とどめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "唱える", "Back": "となえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兎に角", "Back": "とにかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殿様", "Back": "とのさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幕", "Back": "とばり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "帳", "Back": "とばり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "扉", "Back": "とびら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徒歩", "Back": "とほ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乏しい", "Back": "とぼしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "富", "Back": "とみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "富む", "Back": "とむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兎も角", "Back": "ともかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共稼ぎ", "Back": "ともかせぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灯", "Back": "ともしび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伴う", "Back": "ともなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共働き", "Back": "ともばたらき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕らえる", "Back": "とらえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取りあえず", "Back": "とりあえず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り扱い", "Back": "とりあつかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り扱う", "Back": "とりあつかう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鳥居", "Back": "とりい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り替え", "Back": "とりかえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り組む", "Back": "とりくむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り締まり", "Back": "とりしまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り締まる", "Back": "とりしまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り調べる", "Back": "とりしらべる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り立てる", "Back": "とりたてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り次ぐ", "Back": "とりつぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り除く", "Back": "とりのぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り引き", "Back": "とりひき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り巻く", "Back": "とりまく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り混ぜる", "Back": "とりまぜる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り戻す", "Back": "とりもどす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り寄せる", "Back": "とりよせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り分", "Back": "とりわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "副", "Back": "とりわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蕩ける", "Back": "とろける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "胴", "Back": "どう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "働", "Back": "どう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同", "Back": "どう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同意", "Back": "どうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動員", "Back": "どういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同感", "Back": "どうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動機", "Back": "どうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同級", "Back": "どうきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同居", "Back": "どうきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動向", "Back": "どうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同士", "Back": "どうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同志", "Back": "どうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "如何して", "Back": "どうして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "如何しても", "Back": "どうしても", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同情", "Back": "どうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "道場", "Back": "どうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何卒", "Back": "どうぞ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "どうぞ宜しく", "Back": "どうぞよろしく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同調", "Back": "どうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動的", "Back": "どうてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同等", "Back": "どうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "堂々", "Back": "どうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "導入", "Back": "どうにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同封", "Back": "どうふう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同盟", "Back": "どうめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動揺", "Back": "どうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動力", "Back": "どうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独裁", "Back": "どくさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "読者", "Back": "どくしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独自", "Back": "どくじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独占", "Back": "どくせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独創", "Back": "どくそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何処", "Back": "どこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何処か", "Back": "どこか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土産", "Back": "どさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土台", "Back": "どだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何方", "Back": "どちら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土手", "Back": "どて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怒鳴る", "Back": "どなる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何の", "Back": "どの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土俵", "Back": "どひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土木", "Back": "どぼく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何々", "Back": "どれどれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "度忘れ", "Back": "どわすれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鈍感", "Back": "どんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内閣", "Back": "ないかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乃至", "Back": "ないし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内臓", "Back": "ないぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内部", "Back": "ないぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内乱", "Back": "ないらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内陸", "Back": "ないりく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苗", "Back": "なえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尚", "Back": "なお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尚更", "Back": "なおさら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中程", "Back": "なかほど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流し", "Back": "ながし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長々", "Back": "ながなが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殴る", "Back": "なぐる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嘆く", "Back": "なげく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "投げ出す", "Back": "なげだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "和やか", "Back": "なごやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名残", "Back": "なごり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "情け", "Back": "なさけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "情け深い", "Back": "なさけぶかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "為さる", "Back": "なさる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詰る", "Back": "なじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何故", "Back": "なぜ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何故なら", "Back": "なぜなら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名高い", "Back": "なだかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雪崩", "Back": "なだれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "懐く", "Back": "なつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名付ける", "Back": "なづける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何気ない", "Back": "なにげない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何しろ", "Back": "なにしろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何も", "Back": "なにも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何より", "Back": "なにより", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "七日", "Back": "なぬか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名札", "Back": "なふだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生臭い", "Back": "なまぐさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生温い", "Back": "なまぬるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生身", "Back": "なまみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉛", "Back": "なまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鈍る", "Back": "なまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "並み", "Back": "なみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滑らか", "Back": "なめらか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嘗める", "Back": "なめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悩ましい", "Back": "なやましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悩ます", "Back": "なやます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悩み", "Back": "なやみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平均", "Back": "ならし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慣らす", "Back": "ならす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "馴らす", "Back": "ならす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "並びに", "Back": "ならびに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成り立つ", "Back": "なりたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成る丈", "Back": "なるたけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成るべく", "Back": "なるべく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慣れ", "Back": "なれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "馴れ馴れしい", "Back": "なれなれしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "難", "Back": "なん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "南", "Back": "なん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何だか", "Back": "なんだか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何て", "Back": "なんて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何と", "Back": "なんと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何となく", "Back": "なんとなく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何とも", "Back": "なんとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何なり", "Back": "なんなり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "荷", "Back": "に", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "似通う", "Back": "にかよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面皰", "Back": "にきび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賑わう", "Back": "にぎわう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪い", "Back": "にくい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憎しみ", "Back": "にくしみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肉親", "Back": "にくしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肉体", "Back": "にくたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逃げ出す", "Back": "にげだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "西日", "Back": "にしび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滲む", "Back": "にじむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日夜", "Back": "にちや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日当", "Back": "にっとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "荷造り", "Back": "にづくり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "担う", "Back": "になう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "二人", "Back": "ににん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "にも拘らず", "Back": "にもかかわらず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入手", "Back": "にゅうしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入賞", "Back": "にゅうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入浴", "Back": "にゅうよく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尿", "Back": "にょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "俄か", "Back": "にわか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "認識", "Back": "にんしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妊娠", "Back": "にんしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人情", "Back": "にんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "任務", "Back": "にんむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "任命", "Back": "にんめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抜かす", "Back": "ぬかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抜け出す", "Back": "ぬけだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盗み", "Back": "ぬすみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沼", "Back": "ぬま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "音", "Back": "ね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "値打ち", "Back": "ねうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寝かせる", "Back": "ねかせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捻子", "Back": "ねじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ねじ回し", "Back": "ねじまわし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捻じれる", "Back": "ねじれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鼠", "Back": "ねず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妬む", "Back": "ねたむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強請る", "Back": "ねだる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熱湯", "Back": "ねっとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熱意", "Back": "ねつい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熱量", "Back": "ねつりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粘り", "Back": "ねばり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粘る", "Back": "ねばる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "値引き", "Back": "ねびき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "根回し", "Back": "ねまわし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眠たい", "Back": "ねむたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "練る", "Back": "ねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "念", "Back": "ねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年鑑", "Back": "ねんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年号", "Back": "ねんごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "燃焼", "Back": "ねんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年生", "Back": "ねんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年長", "Back": "ねんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "燃料", "Back": "ねんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年輪", "Back": "ねんりん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脳", "Back": "のう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農耕", "Back": "のうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農場", "Back": "のうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農地", "Back": "のうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "納入", "Back": "のうにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逃す", "Back": "のがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逃れる", "Back": "のがれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軒並み", "Back": "のきなみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鋸", "Back": "のこぎり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "望ましい", "Back": "のぞましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "臨む", "Back": "のぞむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗っ取る", "Back": "のっとる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長閑", "Back": "のどか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "罵る", "Back": "ののしる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "延べ", "Back": "のべ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飲み込む", "Back": "のみこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗り換え", "Back": "のりかえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗り込む", "Back": "のりこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刃", "Back": "は", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "派", "Back": "は", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "把握", "Back": "はあく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肺", "Back": "はい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "廃棄", "Back": "はいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配給", "Back": "はいきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配偶者", "Back": "はいぐうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拝啓", "Back": "はいけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "背景", "Back": "はいけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "背後", "Back": "はいご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灰皿", "Back": "はいさら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "廃止", "Back": "はいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拝借", "Back": "はいしゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "排除", "Back": "はいじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "排水", "Back": "はいすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敗戦", "Back": "はいせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配置", "Back": "はいち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配布", "Back": "はいふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配分", "Back": "はいぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配慮", "Back": "はいりょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配列", "Back": "はいれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "映える", "Back": "はえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破壊", "Back": "はかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "墓地", "Back": "はかち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捗る", "Back": "はかどる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "果ない", "Back": "はかない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "諮る", "Back": "はかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "図る", "Back": "はかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剥がす", "Back": "はがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破棄", "Back": "はき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "泊", "Back": "はく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迫害", "Back": "はくがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "薄弱", "Back": "はくじゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "白状", "Back": "はくじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剥ぐ", "Back": "はぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "派遣", "Back": "はけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "励ます", "Back": "はげます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "励む", "Back": "はげむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剥げる", "Back": "はげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鋏", "Back": "はさみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "柱", "Back": "はしら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "橋渡し", "Back": "はしわたし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恥", "Back": "はじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弾く", "Back": "はじく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "始め", "Back": "はじめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "始めまして", "Back": "はじめまして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恥じらう", "Back": "はじらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恥じる", "Back": "はじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蓮", "Back": "はす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "筈", "Back": "はず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弾む", "Back": "はずむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破損", "Back": "はそん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "機", "Back": "はた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "果たして", "Back": "はたして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "果たす", "Back": "はたす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裸足", "Back": "はだし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蜂蜜", "Back": "はちみつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発掘", "Back": "はっくつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発生", "Back": "はっせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発足", "Back": "はっそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "初", "Back": "はつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発", "Back": "はつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発育", "Back": "はついく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発芽", "Back": "はつが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発言", "Back": "はつげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発病", "Back": "はつびょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "初耳", "Back": "はつみみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "果て", "Back": "はて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "果てる", "Back": "はてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "話し合い", "Back": "はなしあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甚だ", "Back": "はなはだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "華々しい", "Back": "はなばなしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "花びら", "Back": "はなびら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "華やか", "Back": "はなやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "阻む", "Back": "はばむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浜", "Back": "はま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浜辺", "Back": "はまべ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "填まる", "Back": "はまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歯磨", "Back": "はみがき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "填める", "Back": "はめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生やす", "Back": "はやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "早める", "Back": "はやめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流行", "Back": "はやり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腹立ち", "Back": "はらだち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原っぱ", "Back": "はらっぱ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "張り紙", "Back": "はりがみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遥か", "Back": "はるか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破裂", "Back": "はれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腫れる", "Back": "はれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "班", "Back": "はん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "判", "Back": "はん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "版", "Back": "はん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繁栄", "Back": "はんえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反感", "Back": "はんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "版画", "Back": "はんが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反響", "Back": "はんきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "判決", "Back": "はんけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反撃", "Back": "はんげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反射", "Back": "はんしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繁殖", "Back": "はんしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繁盛", "Back": "はんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反する", "Back": "はんする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "判定", "Back": "はんてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反応", "Back": "はんのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "半端", "Back": "はんぱ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反発", "Back": "はんぱつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反乱", "Back": "はんらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "氾濫", "Back": "はんらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "黴菌", "Back": "ばいきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賠償", "Back": "ばいしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "倍率", "Back": "ばいりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "馬鹿馬鹿しい", "Back": "ばかばかしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "馬鹿らしい", "Back": "ばからしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漠然", "Back": "ばくぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "爆弾", "Back": "ばくだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "爆破", "Back": "ばくは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暴露", "Back": "ばくろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "化ける", "Back": "ばける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "罰", "Back": "ばち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伐", "Back": "ばつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発条", "Back": "ばね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "散蒔く", "Back": "ばらまく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "万", "Back": "ばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "万人", "Back": "ばんじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "万能", "Back": "ばんのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "番目", "Back": "ばんめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "非", "Back": "ひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "費", "Back": "ひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "延いては", "Back": "ひいては", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "控室", "Back": "ひかえしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "控える", "Back": "ひかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悲観", "Back": "ひかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "匹", "Back": "ひき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引き上げる", "Back": "ひきあげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "率いる", "Back": "ひきいる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引き受ける", "Back": "ひきうける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引き起こす", "Back": "ひきおこす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引き下げる", "Back": "ひきさげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引きずる", "Back": "ひきずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引き取る", "Back": "ひきとる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引き分け", "Back": "ひきわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "否決", "Back": "ひけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "非行", "Back": "ひこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日頃", "Back": "ひごろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "久しい", "Back": "ひさしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "久し振り", "Back": "ひさしぶり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悲惨", "Back": "ひさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "秘書", "Back": "ひしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "比重", "Back": "ひじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "密か", "Back": "ひそか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浸す", "Back": "ひたす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一向", "Back": "ひたすら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "左利き", "Back": "ひだりきき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引っ掻く", "Back": "ひっかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引っ掛ける", "Back": "ひっかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "必修", "Back": "ひっしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "匹敵", "Back": "ひってき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未", "Back": "ひつじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "必然", "Back": "ひつぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一息", "Back": "ひといき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単", "Back": "ひとえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人柄", "Back": "ひとがら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一頃", "Back": "ひところ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人質", "Back": "ひとじち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一筋", "Back": "ひとすき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一まず", "Back": "ひとまず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一人でに", "Back": "ひとりでに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酷い", "Back": "ひどい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日取り", "Back": "ひどり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雛", "Back": "ひな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日向", "Back": "ひなた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "避難", "Back": "ひなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "非難", "Back": "ひなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日の丸", "Back": "ひのまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火花", "Back": "ひばな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日々", "Back": "ひび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悲鳴", "Back": "ひめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "百科事典", "Back": "ひゃっかじてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "百科辞典", "Back": "ひゃっかじてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷やかす", "Back": "ひやかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日焼け", "Back": "ひやけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "票", "Back": "ひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "標語", "Back": "ひょうご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平たい", "Back": "ひらたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "比率", "Back": "ひりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肥料", "Back": "ひりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "比例", "Back": "ひれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "疲労", "Back": "ひろう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広まる", "Back": "ひろまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貧困", "Back": "ひんこん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "品質", "Back": "ひんしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "品種", "Back": "ひんしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貧弱", "Back": "ひんじゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頻繁", "Back": "ひんぱん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "美", "Back": "び", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "微笑", "Back": "びしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "美術", "Back": "びじゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吃驚", "Back": "びっくり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "描写", "Back": "びょうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "微量", "Back": "びりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敏感", "Back": "びんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貧乏", "Back": "びんぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歩", "Back": "ふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不意", "Back": "ふい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "封", "Back": "ふう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "封鎖", "Back": "ふうさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風習", "Back": "ふうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風俗", "Back": "ふうぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風土", "Back": "ふうど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不可欠", "Back": "ふかけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "深める", "Back": "ふかめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不吉", "Back": "ふきつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不況", "Back": "ふきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "布巾", "Back": "ふきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "福", "Back": "ふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "復旧", "Back": "ふくきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "複合", "Back": "ふくごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "福祉", "Back": "ふくし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覆面", "Back": "ふくめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膨れる", "Back": "ふくれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不景気", "Back": "ふけいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "老ける", "Back": "ふける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "布告", "Back": "ふこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "富豪", "Back": "ふごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "負債", "Back": "ふさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相応しい", "Back": "ふさわしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不在", "Back": "ふざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不山戯る", "Back": "ふざける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "負傷", "Back": "ふしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不審", "Back": "ふしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不振", "Back": "ふしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不順", "Back": "ふじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付属", "Back": "ふぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "負担", "Back": "ふたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不調", "Back": "ふちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "復活", "Back": "ふっかつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "復興", "Back": "ふっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沸騰", "Back": "ふっとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仏", "Back": "ふつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不図", "Back": "ふと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不当", "Back": "ふとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不動産", "Back": "ふどうさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "赴任", "Back": "ふにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腐敗", "Back": "ふはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不評", "Back": "ふひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不便", "Back": "ふびん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不服", "Back": "ふふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "普遍", "Back": "ふへん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "踏まえる", "Back": "ふまえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文", "Back": "ふみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不明", "Back": "ふめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "扶養", "Back": "ふよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "振り", "Back": "ふり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "振り出し", "Back": "ふりだし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不良", "Back": "ふりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浮力", "Back": "ふりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "震わせる", "Back": "ふるわせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付録", "Back": "ふろく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分", "Back": "ふん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憤慨", "Back": "ふんがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紛失", "Back": "ふんしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "噴出", "Back": "ふんしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紛争", "Back": "ふんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奮闘", "Back": "ふんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粉末", "Back": "ふんまつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "部", "Back": "ぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "部下", "Back": "ぶか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "侮辱", "Back": "ぶじょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "武装", "Back": "ぶそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "斑", "Back": "ぶち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物資", "Back": "ぶっし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物体", "Back": "ぶったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物議", "Back": "ぶつぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打付ける", "Back": "ぶつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仏像", "Back": "ぶつぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無難", "Back": "ぶなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "部門", "Back": "ぶもん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ぶら下げる", "Back": "ぶらさげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "武力", "Back": "ぶりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無礼", "Back": "ぶれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文化財", "Back": "ぶんかざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分業", "Back": "ぶんぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文語", "Back": "ぶんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分散", "Back": "ぶんさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分子", "Back": "ぶんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文書", "Back": "ぶんしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分担", "Back": "ぶんたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分配", "Back": "ぶんぱい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分母", "Back": "ぶんぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分離", "Back": "ぶんり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分裂", "Back": "ぶんれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兵器", "Back": "へいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "閉口", "Back": "へいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平行", "Back": "へいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "閉鎖", "Back": "へいさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兵士", "Back": "へいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平常", "Back": "へいじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平方", "Back": "へいほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "並列", "Back": "へいれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辟易", "Back": "へきえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "臍", "Back": "へそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "隔たる", "Back": "へだたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "謙る", "Back": "へりくだる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経る", "Back": "へる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "編", "Back": "へん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偏", "Back": "へん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "変革", "Back": "へんかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "返還", "Back": "へんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偏見", "Back": "へんけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "返済", "Back": "へんさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "変遷", "Back": "へんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "返答", "Back": "へんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "変動", "Back": "へんどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弁解", "Back": "べんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "便宜", "Back": "べんぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弁護", "Back": "べんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弁償", "Back": "べんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弁論", "Back": "べんろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "穂", "Back": "ほ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保育", "Back": "ほいく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "倣", "Back": "ほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "法案", "Back": "ほうあん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "崩壊", "Back": "ほうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "法学", "Back": "ほうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放棄", "Back": "ほうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宝器", "Back": "ほうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "封建", "Back": "ほうけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "豊作", "Back": "ほうさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方策", "Back": "ほうさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奉仕", "Back": "ほうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方式", "Back": "ほうしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放射", "Back": "ほうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放射能", "Back": "ほうしゃのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "報酬", "Back": "ほうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放出", "Back": "ほうしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "報じる", "Back": "ほうじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "報ずる", "Back": "ほうずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放置", "Back": "ほうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "法廷", "Back": "ほうてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "報道", "Back": "ほうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "褒美", "Back": "ほうび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "葬る", "Back": "ほうむる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放り込む", "Back": "ほうりこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放り出す", "Back": "ほうりだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飽和", "Back": "ほうわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保温", "Back": "ほおん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕獲", "Back": "ほかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保管", "Back": "ほかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "補給", "Back": "ほきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "補強", "Back": "ほきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保険", "Back": "ほけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕鯨", "Back": "ほげい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誇る", "Back": "ほこる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "綻びる", "Back": "ほころびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保護", "Back": "ほご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "干し物", "Back": "ほしもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保守", "Back": "ほしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保障", "Back": "ほしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "補償", "Back": "ほしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "補充", "Back": "ほじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "補助", "Back": "ほじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "舗装", "Back": "ほそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "補足", "Back": "ほそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発作", "Back": "ほっさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頬っぺた", "Back": "ほっぺた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辺り", "Back": "ほとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殆ど", "Back": "ほとんど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解く", "Back": "ほどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "施す", "Back": "ほどこす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保母", "Back": "ほぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保養", "Back": "ほよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕吏", "Back": "ほり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕虜", "Back": "ほりょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滅びる", "Back": "ほろびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滅ぼす", "Back": "ほろぼす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本格", "Back": "ほんかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本館", "Back": "ほんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本気", "Back": "ほんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本質", "Back": "ほんしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本体", "Back": "ほんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本音", "Back": "ほんね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本の", "Back": "ほんの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本能", "Back": "ほんのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本場", "Back": "ほんば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本文", "Back": "ほんぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本名", "Back": "ほんみょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "卯", "Back": "ぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "防衛", "Back": "ぼうえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "防火", "Back": "ぼうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妨害", "Back": "ぼうがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紡績", "Back": "ぼうせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呆然", "Back": "ぼうぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膨脹", "Back": "ぼうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冒頭", "Back": "ぼうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暴動", "Back": "ぼうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暴風", "Back": "ぼうふう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暴力", "Back": "ぼうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "募金", "Back": "ぼきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "牧師", "Back": "ぼくし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "母校", "Back": "ぼこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "没収", "Back": "ぼっしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "坊ちゃん", "Back": "ぼっちゃん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "没落", "Back": "ぼつらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "藍褸", "Back": "ぼろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "枚", "Back": "まい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "埋蔵", "Back": "まいぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "舞う", "Back": "まう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真上", "Back": "まうえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前売り", "Back": "まえうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前置き", "Back": "まえおき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前もって", "Back": "まえもって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "任す", "Back": "まかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "負かす", "Back": "まかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賄う", "Back": "まかなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "曲がる", "Back": "まがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巻", "Back": "まき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紛らわしい", "Back": "まぎらわしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紛れる", "Back": "まぎれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膜", "Back": "まく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捲る", "Back": "まくる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真心", "Back": "まこころ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誠", "Back": "まこと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真に", "Back": "まことに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正しく", "Back": "まさしく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正に", "Back": "まさに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勝る", "Back": "まさる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増し", "Back": "まし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真下", "Back": "ました", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "況して", "Back": "まして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交える", "Back": "まじえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交わる", "Back": "まじわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "麻酔", "Back": "ますい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "益々", "Back": "ますます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不味い", "Back": "まずい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "股", "Back": "また", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "跨がる", "Back": "またがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "跨ぐ", "Back": "またぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瞬き", "Back": "またたき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "待ち合わせ", "Back": "まちあわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間違う", "Back": "まちがう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "待ち遠しい", "Back": "まちどおしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "待ち望む", "Back": "まちのぞむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区々", "Back": "まちまち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "末期", "Back": "まっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ二つ", "Back": "まっぷたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "纏まり", "Back": "まとまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "纏め", "Back": "まとめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "免れる", "Back": "まぬかれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "招き", "Back": "まねき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "麻痺", "Back": "まひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眩しい", "Back": "まぶしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目蓋", "Back": "まぶた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間々", "Back": "まま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間もなく", "Back": "まもなく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眉", "Back": "まゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鞠", "Back": "まり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丸ごと", "Back": "まるごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丸っきり", "Back": "まるっきり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丸で", "Back": "まるで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丸々", "Back": "まるまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丸める", "Back": "まるめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "満月", "Back": "まんげつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "満場", "Back": "まんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真ん中", "Back": "まんなか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真ん前", "Back": "まんまえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真ん丸い", "Back": "まんまるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "三", "Back": "み", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見合い", "Back": "みあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見合わせる", "Back": "みあわせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見落とす", "Back": "みおとす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未開", "Back": "みかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "味覚", "Back": "みかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見掛ける", "Back": "みかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "三日月", "Back": "みかずき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見方", "Back": "みかた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見苦しい", "Back": "みぐるしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見込み", "Back": "みこみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未婚", "Back": "みこん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "惨め", "Back": "みじめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未熟", "Back": "みじゅく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "微塵", "Back": "みじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見すぼらしい", "Back": "みすぼらしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見せびらかす", "Back": "みせびらかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見せ物", "Back": "みせもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "満たす", "Back": "みたす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乱す", "Back": "みだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乱れる", "Back": "みだれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未知", "Back": "みち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "導く", "Back": "みちびく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身近", "Back": "みぢか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "密集", "Back": "みっしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "密接", "Back": "みっせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見っともない", "Back": "みっともない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蜜", "Back": "みつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "密度", "Back": "みつど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見積り", "Back": "みつもり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未定", "Back": "みてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見通し", "Back": "みとおし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "源", "Back": "みなもと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身なり", "Back": "みなり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "峰", "Back": "みね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見逃す", "Back": "みのがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見晴らし", "Back": "みはらし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身振り", "Back": "みぶり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見舞", "Back": "みまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脈", "Back": "みゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未練", "Back": "みれん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見渡す", "Back": "みわたす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "民主", "Back": "みんしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "民宿", "Back": "みんしゅく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "民族", "Back": "みんぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "民俗", "Back": "みんぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "六", "Back": "む", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無意味", "Back": "むいみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "向き", "Back": "むき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無口", "Back": "むくち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "向け", "Back": "むけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "婿", "Back": "むこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無効", "Back": "むこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無言", "Back": "むごん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "毟る", "Back": "むしる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無邪気", "Back": "むじゃき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結び", "Back": "むすび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結び付き", "Back": "むすびつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結び付く", "Back": "むすびつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結び付ける", "Back": "むすびつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無線", "Back": "むせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無駄遣い", "Back": "むだづかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無断", "Back": "むだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無知", "Back": "むち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無茶", "Back": "むちゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無茶苦茶", "Back": "むちゃくちゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空しい", "Back": "むなしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無念", "Back": "むねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無能", "Back": "むのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無闇に", "Back": "むやみに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無用", "Back": "むよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "群がる", "Back": "むらがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無論", "Back": "むろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名産", "Back": "めいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名称", "Back": "めいしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "命中", "Back": "めいちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名簿", "Back": "めいぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名誉", "Back": "めいよ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明瞭", "Back": "めいりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明朗", "Back": "めいろう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目方", "Back": "めかた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恵み", "Back": "めぐみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恵む", "Back": "めぐむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目覚しい", "Back": "めざましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目覚める", "Back": "めざめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "召す", "Back": "めす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雌", "Back": "めす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滅茶苦茶", "Back": "めちゃくちゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目付き", "Back": "めつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滅亡", "Back": "めつぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愛でたい", "Back": "めでたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目眩", "Back": "めまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目盛", "Back": "めもり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面会", "Back": "めんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "免除", "Back": "めんじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面する", "Back": "めんする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面目", "Back": "めんぼく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "設ける", "Back": "もうける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申し入れる", "Back": "もうしいれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申し込み", "Back": "もうしこみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申出", "Back": "もうしで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申し出る", "Back": "もうしでる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申し分", "Back": "もうしぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盲点", "Back": "もうてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "猛烈", "Back": "もうれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "藻掻く", "Back": "もがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目録", "Back": "もくろく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目論見", "Back": "もくろみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "模型", "Back": "もけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "模索", "Back": "もさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若し", "Back": "もし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若しかしたら", "Back": "もしかしたら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若しかして", "Back": "もしかして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若しかすると", "Back": "もしかすると", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若しくは", "Back": "もしくは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若しも", "Back": "もしも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "齎らす", "Back": "もたらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凭れる", "Back": "もたれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "持ち", "Back": "もち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "持ち切り", "Back": "もちきり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物体ない", "Back": "もったいない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "以て", "Back": "もって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "専ら", "Back": "もっぱら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "持て成す", "Back": "もてなす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "持てる", "Back": "もてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基", "Back": "もとい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物置き", "Back": "ものおき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物好き", "Back": "ものずき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物足りない", "Back": "ものたりない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "最早", "Back": "もはや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "模範", "Back": "もはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "模倣", "Back": "もほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揉める", "Back": "もめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腿", "Back": "もも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "催す", "Back": "もよおす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漏らす", "Back": "もらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盛り上がる", "Back": "もりあがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漏る", "Back": "もる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漏れる", "Back": "もれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脆い", "Back": "もろい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "問", "Back": "もん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "矢", "Back": "や", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "哉", "Back": "や", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "喧しい", "Back": "やかましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "野外", "Back": "やがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軈て", "Back": "やがて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜行", "Back": "やぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役職", "Back": "やくしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役立つ", "Back": "やくだつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役場", "Back": "やくば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜具", "Back": "やぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優", "Back": "やさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屋敷", "Back": "やしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "養う", "Back": "やしなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "社", "Back": "やしろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "野心", "Back": "やしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "易い", "Back": "やすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "安っぽい", "Back": "やすっぽい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休める", "Back": "やすめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "野生", "Back": "やせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "矢鱈に", "Back": "やたらに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜中", "Back": "やちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奴", "Back": "やっこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "やっ付ける", "Back": "やっつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "矢っ張り", "Back": "やっぱり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "野党", "Back": "やとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "病", "Back": "やまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "闇", "Back": "やみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "病む", "Back": "やむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "止むを得ない", "Back": "やむをえない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "稍", "Back": "やや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遣り通す", "Back": "やりとおす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "やり遂げる", "Back": "やりとげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遣る", "Back": "やる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "和らげる", "Back": "やわらげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優位", "Back": "ゆうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憂鬱", "Back": "ゆううつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有益", "Back": "ゆうえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優越", "Back": "ゆうえつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勇敢", "Back": "ゆうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有機", "Back": "ゆうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夕暮れ", "Back": "ゆうぐれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "融資", "Back": "ゆうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有する", "Back": "ゆうする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "融通", "Back": "ゆうずう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優勢", "Back": "ゆうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優先", "Back": "ゆうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誘導", "Back": "ゆうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優美", "Back": "ゆうび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有望", "Back": "ゆうぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遊牧", "Back": "ゆうぼく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夕焼け", "Back": "ゆうやけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有力", "Back": "ゆうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幽霊", "Back": "ゆうれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誘惑", "Back": "ゆうわく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揺さぶる", "Back": "ゆさぶる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茹でる", "Back": "ゆでる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指差す", "Back": "ゆびさす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弓", "Back": "ゆみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揺らぐ", "Back": "ゆらぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緩む", "Back": "ゆるむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緩める", "Back": "ゆるめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緩やか", "Back": "ゆるやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世", "Back": "よ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好い", "Back": "よい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要因", "Back": "よういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溶液", "Back": "ようえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用件", "Back": "ようけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "養護", "Back": "ようご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用紙", "Back": "ようし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "様式", "Back": "ようしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要する", "Back": "ようする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要請", "Back": "ようせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "養成", "Back": "ようせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "様相", "Back": "ようそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用品", "Back": "ようひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "洋風", "Back": "ようふう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用法", "Back": "ようほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要望", "Back": "ようぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余暇", "Back": "よか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予感", "Back": "よかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余興", "Back": "よきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "預金", "Back": "よきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抑圧", "Back": "よくあつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浴室", "Back": "よくしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抑制", "Back": "よくせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欲深い", "Back": "よくふかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欲望", "Back": "よくぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寄こす", "Back": "よこす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "横綱", "Back": "よこづな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "葦", "Back": "よし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "善し悪し", "Back": "よしあし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予想", "Back": "よそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余所見", "Back": "よそみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余地", "Back": "よち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "依って", "Back": "よって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余程", "Back": "よっぽど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "与党", "Back": "よとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呼び止める", "Back": "よびとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜更かし", "Back": "よふかし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜更け", "Back": "よふけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "読み上げる", "Back": "よみあげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寄り掛かる", "Back": "よりかかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宜しく", "Back": "よろしく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弱まる", "Back": "よわまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弱める", "Back": "よわめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弱る", "Back": "よわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "来場", "Back": "らいじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酪農", "Back": "らくのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落下", "Back": "らっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "楽観", "Back": "らっかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濫用", "Back": "らんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "理屈", "Back": "りくつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利根", "Back": "りこん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利子", "Back": "りし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利潤", "Back": "りじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "理性", "Back": "りせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利息", "Back": "りそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立体", "Back": "りったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立法", "Back": "りっぽう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利点", "Back": "りてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "略語", "Back": "りゃくご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "略奪", "Back": "りゃくだつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流", "Back": "りゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流通", "Back": "りゅうつう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "了", "Back": "りょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "料", "Back": "りょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "領域", "Back": "りょういき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "了解", "Back": "りょうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "領海", "Back": "りょうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "両極", "Back": "りょうきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "良好", "Back": "りょうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "良識", "Back": "りょうしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "良質", "Back": "りょうしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "了承", "Back": "りょうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "良心", "Back": "りょうしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "領地", "Back": "りょうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "領土", "Back": "りょうど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "両立", "Back": "りょうりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旅客", "Back": "りょかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旅券", "Back": "りょけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "履歴", "Back": "りれき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "理論", "Back": "りろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "輪", "Back": "りん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "林業", "Back": "りんぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "類似", "Back": "るいじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "類推", "Back": "るいすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷酷", "Back": "れいこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷蔵", "Back": "れいぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷淡", "Back": "れいたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恋愛", "Back": "れんあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連休", "Back": "れんきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連日", "Back": "れんじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連中", "Back": "れんじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連帯", "Back": "れんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連邦", "Back": "れんぽう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連盟", "Back": "れんめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "老衰", "Back": "ろうすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "朗読", "Back": "ろうどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浪費", "Back": "ろうひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "労力", "Back": "ろうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "碌な", "Back": "ろくな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "碌に", "Back": "ろくに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "露骨", "Back": "ろこつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "論議", "Back": "ろんぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "論理", "Back": "ろんり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "和", "Back": "わ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "我がまま", "Back": "わがまま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "枠", "Back": "わく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "惑星", "Back": "わくせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "技", "Back": "わざ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "態と", "Back": "わざと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "態々", "Back": "わざわざ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煩わしい", "Back": "わずらわしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "渡り鳥", "Back": "わたりどり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詫び", "Back": "わび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "和風", "Back": "わふう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "和文", "Back": "わぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "藁", "Back": "わら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割合に", "Back": "わりあいに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割り当て", "Back": "わりあて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割り込む", "Back": "わりこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割り算", "Back": "わりざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割引き", "Back": "わりびき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪者", "Back": "わるもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ローマ字", "Back": "ローマじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n1-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{}]
